片名：胡佛  翻譯：米粒@豆瓣 weibo@conanemily  交流分享 請勿商用 保護版權 人人有責
Let me tell you something.
[胡佛]這麼跟你說吧
The SCLC has direct Communist ties.
南方基督教領袖會議和共產主義有直接聯繫
Even great men can be corrupted,  can't they?
最偉大的人也有腐壞的可能  不是嗎？
Communism is not a political party.  It is a disease.
共產主義並不是政治黨派的一種  這是瘟疫
It corrupts the soul,  turning even the gentlest of men...
它會腐蝕靈魂  把最紳士的人們...
...into vicious, evil tyrants.
...變成惡毒、邪惡的暴君
What we are seeing is a pervasive  contempt for law and order.
我們所見到的全是  對法律和指令的不屑一顧
Crime rates are soaring.
犯罪率激增
There's widespread,  open defiance of our authority...
廣泛、公然地蔑視我們的權威...
...and, mark my words,  if this goes unchecked...
...記住我這句話  倘若此事不被及時遏制
...it will once again plunge our nation  into the depths of anarchy.
它會把我們國家再次  拉向無政府狀態的深淵
It all starts out peacefully,  doesn't it, Mr. lrwin?
一切的開始總是平靜的  不是嗎，埃爾文先生？
You have to live with the fact...
你必須接受這個事實...
...that you could've helped prevent  the bombings and the violence.
...那就是你本可以幫著避免  爆炸案和暴力事件的發生
I'm more interested in what this says  about your FBl.
我更感興趣的是  它是如何描述您和您掌管的聯邦調查局
I have worked too long and hard  to just sit back...
我辛苦工作了這麼長時間  真的不能就這樣退居幕後...
...and watch the bad guys capture  the spotlight again, haven't I?
...來眼睜睜地看著壞人再次吸引  大家的眼球 不是嗎？
The funny thing about notoriety...
關於臭名昭著這件事  有件有趣的事實...
...especially the kind that needs adoration,  fame for fame's sake...
...尤其是當它的來源是崇拜  或是名望...
...if unchecked,  it inevitably leads to villainy.
...如果不加以控制  將不可避免地變成壞事
I suggest you look at what this  squabble is really about...
我建議您好好看看  這次爭辯的真正目的...
...before you destroy the reputation  of the thing we both know you love most.
...在徹底毀掉您最心愛的事情的名聲之前  我們都知道那是什麼
[對講機響]
Sir, the writer's here from Crime Records...
[海倫]來自《犯罪紀實》的作者到了
...the PR Department.
...公關辦公室找來的
Set him up with a typewriter  in my outer office.
把他安排在我外面的辦公室  帶上打字機
Miss Gandy, it's time this generation  learn my side of the story.
甘迪小姐 是時候讓這代人  知道我這版本的故事了
- Right away.  - Thank you.
- [海倫]馬上就好  - 謝謝
In 1919, Agent Smith...
那是1919年，史密斯調查員...
...my first boss here  at the Department of Justice...
我在司法部的第一任上司...
...was Attorney General  A. Mitchell Palmer.
是總檢察長A·米切爾·帕爾默
He was a Quaker.
他是貴格會信仰者  （貴格會，基督教信教的一個派別）
He didn't believe in war, but he understood  the necessity of strength and resolve.
他不信奉戰爭  但他理解力量和決斷的必要性
Believe what you will from historians...
你們從史學家那裡瞭解到的...
...most write from a present perspective,  forgetting context.
...通常都是從現在的角度來看  疏忽了前後關係
Mitchell Palmer was a hero.
米切爾·帕爾默是個英雄人物
- Are you all right?  - Unh.
- 你沒事吧？  - 嗯
- Are you all right?  - Yes. I think. Yes.
- 沒事吧？  - 我想是的，是的
It's all right. Come here.
沒事了 來
- It's all right, it's all right.  - No, it's okay.
- 沒事了 沒事了  - 沒事了
Are you okay? It's okay.
還好嗎？已經沒事了
Are you okay?
還好吧？
You see,  Palmer fought the radicals, just as I have.
你看 帕爾默和激進者的鬥爭  正和我一樣
And just as I have, he was targeted.  He wasn't alone.
同樣的 他也是目標  他並不是唯一一個
Across the country that night,  eight bombs exploded, all at 11 p.m.
那一晚全國各地一共  有8枚炸彈爆炸 全都是在晚上11點
Two United States senators...
兩位國家參議員
...four cabinet members,  a Supreme Court justice...
四位內閣成員  一位最高法院法官
...John D. Rockefeller, J.P. Morgan...
約翰·D·洛克菲勒，J·P·摩根...  （洛克菲勒，美國實業家，標準石油創辦人；摩根，美國銀行家）
...all of them targeted  by Bolshevik Communists.
他們都成了  布爾什維克共產主義分子的目標
Yeah, it shook the whole thing.
是啊 整棟樓都晃了
It was clear to me  the radical's bomb went off too soon...
對我而言 激進者的炸彈襲擊事件  過去得太快了
...leaving only his blood in the street.
只在路中間留下了他的血跡
But the inspectors used buckets to  clean up the mess instead of collecting it.
但是檢察人員用桶子來收拾殘局  而不是收集證據
They discarded his gun  instead of preserving its prints.
他們丟掉了他的槍  而不是保存指紋
But you see,  this wasn't clumsy police work.
但是你也看得到  這不算什麼愚蠢的警察的行為
In those times, it was normal procedure.
在那個時候  這是正常的程序
This may be the end of days  for this country, Dwight.
這個國家或許就要完了 德懷特
it was 1919, before anyone  respected criminal science...
那是1919年  還沒人正視過犯罪科學...
...before federal powers, before the FBl.
還沒有聯邦權利機構  沒有聯邦調查局
It was that night my eyes were opened.  That very night.
就是那晚我的眼界被打開了  就是那一晚
Is he a neighbor, sir?
他是你的鄰居嗎？
No. He works in my office.
不 他在我辦公室工作
- "There will have to be murder.  - We will kill because it is necessary.
「會有一次謀殺行動  我們殺戮因為它必須存在」
We will destroy to rid the world  of your tyrannical institutions."
「我們以毀滅來擺脫  你們這個獨裁主義的國家」
You were at Attorney General  Palmer's home that night?
你那晚在帕爾默檢察長的家裡？
Well, let's leave that  to the reader's imagination.
我們把這一點  留給讀者想像吧
You see, it's important we give  our protagonist a bit of mystery.
你看 我們賦予主角一些神秘感  還是很重要的
I could allude to a young man  who matches your description.
我可以暗示是一個  您提到過的年輕人
The best of both worlds.
對兩邊都好
Where did you get your law degree?
你的法學文憑是哪裡的？
George Washington. I grew up here.
喬治華盛頓大學  我是本地人
I had a mom to take care of,  so I stayed close.
我需要照顧家母  所以不敢遠遊
I received an English degree there also.
我在這學校還取得了英語專業文憑
Then I don't need to tell you that  what determines a man's legacy...
那就不需要我來告訴你  決定一個人的遺產的關鍵...
...is often what isn't seen.
通常都是眼睛所不能看見的
What's critical at this moment is...
現在的重點是
...that we re-clarify the difference  between villain and hero.
我們要重申  惡棍和英雄的區別
How do you think that compares  with today?
你覺得這區別  和今天的標準相比呢？
I'm not sure, sir. I'd like to hear more.
我也不確定  我想要知道更多
I could come back tomorrow.
我可以明天再來
Fine. But the pages stay here.
好 但這些寫好的得留下
Of course, sir.
當然
Agent Smith.
再會 史密斯調查員
Thank you, sir.
謝謝您
Never a good idea to talk too loud.
太大聲說話總是不好的
Good morning, John.
早上好 約翰
Mr. Palmer has asked that you attend  the emergency meeting today.
帕爾默先生讓你參與今天的緊急會議
Miss Gladwell, please remember...
格萊德維爾小姐 請記住...
...it's Mr. Hoover.
叫我 胡佛先生
Two o'clock.
兩點鐘
Don't be too early this time.  It's as rude as being tardy.
這次別去太早  跟遲到一樣無禮
And who is this lovely addition  to the secretarial pool?
這位秘書處新來的美麗女士又是？
Helen, introduce yourself.
海倫 自我介紹一下
Oh.
噢
Pleased to meet you, Mr. Hoover.  I'm Helen Gandy.
很高興見到你 胡佛先生  我叫海倫·甘迪
Pleased to meet you.  Welcome to the Department of Justice.
也很高興見到你  歡迎來司法部
You can notify Mr. Palmer  that I will attend.
你可以告知帕爾默先生我會出席
Of course.
當然
- He's always a charmer.  - I wouldn't take anything very seriously.
他總是這麼迷人  我做事不會太認真的
Jeremy, I need your help.
傑瑞米 我需要你的幫助
I need, uh... Uh, help.
我需要...幫助
I need your help.
我需要你的幫助
Good evening, Mother.
晚上好 母親
Edgar.
埃德加
Madame Marcia held court this morning.
瑪西亞夫人今早給我算了一卦
I should buy a dress.
她預感說  我應該買條裙子
She says your father will die soon.
她說你的父親不久就要死了
And when he does, you will rise to be  the most powerful man in the country.
他死後  你會成為這個國家最有權勢的人
Your brother's a good man, Edgar...
你的哥哥是個好人  埃德加...
...but you will restore our family  to greatness.
但是你會讓我們家族復興
Edgar?
埃德加？
Edgar? Am I boring you?
埃德加？我煩到你了嗎？
I'm listening, Mother. You fired the maid.
我在聽著呢 媽媽  你解雇了女傭
I told her when she was through,  she could quit.
我告訴她幹完活  就可以自己走人了
I'm not paying for her impudence.  The whole Negro race is in open revolt.
我不會再為她的肆無忌憚付工錢  整個黑人階級都要公開造反了
- I could open an investigation.  - Gotten too comfortable.
- 我可以開展調查  - 日子過得太舒服了
Did you hear what I said?  I said I could open an investigation.
你聽見我剛才說的了嗎？  我說 我可以開展調查了
Say what you mean.
直說吧什麼意思
Mr. Palmer called me into a meeting today.  The war against the Bolsheviks has begun.
帕爾默先生今天叫我參與了一個會議  和布爾什維克的戰爭已經開始了
He's insisted that I lead  a new anti-radical division.
他堅持讓我領導  一個新的反激進分子的部門
Did you leap like a dog?
你是不是像條小狗一樣歡呼雀躍了？
I told him this is the greatest  threat our nation has ever faced...
我告訴他  這是我們國家面臨過的最大威脅...
...and I cannot take the job unless  I feel certain I can be effective.
我在感覺到自己會有所成效之前  是不會接受這份工作的
Well done. But you'll take it.
漂亮 但你還是會接受的
Three thousand a year, Mother.
年薪有三千呢 媽
I've got to get new clothes.  You can't look like that anymore.
我得給你買點新衣服  你不能再穿成這樣了
I have 40 names of suspected radicals  already in only four hours.
僅僅4小時之後  我就掌握了40個激進分子的名單
I should have 10,000  by end of the month.
月底之前應該會有一萬個
And I have my own staff, trusted agents.
我還有自己的員工  可以信任的調查員們
Edgar, are you smoking?
埃德加 你在抽煙？
- Doesn't come naturally, Mother.  - Listen to the doctor.
- 不會自覺去抽的 媽  - 聽醫生的話
With this new burden,  your nerves could get the better of you.
有它分散一下  你的勇氣會更迸發出來
You don't want to end up like your father.
你不會想落得跟你爸一樣的下場吧
Go and try one now.  You can put your father in his room.
現在就去抽根煙  把你爸扶到房間去
I have to get ready for dinner.
我得準備一下去吃晚飯
Are you abandoning me tonight?
今晚你要拋下我？
It's with a typist. She's very organized.
是和一位打字員  她很有條理
Is it a date?
這是個約會？
I think so. I think so.
我想是的
I'm gonna show her my old card catalog  system at the Library of Congress.
我會給她展示我在國會圖書館的  卡片編目系統
Romance her.
給她製造點浪漫
Wear a blue tie.
戴藍色的領帶
You look so handsome in your blue tie.
你戴藍色領帶特別帥
Look at the ceiling.
看天花板
It's incredible.
真不可思議
I've never been here before.
我還從沒來過這裡
I helped organize it.
我幫忙整編好了這些
See, every item is assigned  its own index card...
看 每件物品都有它  自己的索引卡片
...with its own unique code...
有著自己特有的編碼
...indicating the title, author,  location, and topic.
標明了標題 作者 位置 主題
What used to take days to locate  now only takes a matter of minutes.
過去需要好幾天時間來找的東西  現在只需要幾分鐘
Go on. Give me an author  or a topic. Anything.
來吧 說個作者或者題目 隨便什麼
Indiscretion.
「不檢點行為」
What era?
什麼年代？
Present day.
現代
Good. Time me.
好 幫我計時
Hmm.
嗯...
Heh.
Almost there, heh.
差不多找到了
How do you know I didn't mean  political indiscretion?
你怎麼知道我不是在說  「政治不檢點」？
Well, if you'd like,  I can start all over again.
如果你喜歡呢  我可以重找一次
This will do.
這個就好了
How long did I take?
我花了多長時間？
One minute, 10 seconds.
一分鐘 零10秒
Now imagine if every citizen in this country  were uniquely identifiable...
想像一下 如果這個國家的每個公民  都可以如此唯一可識別...
...by their own card and number,  say, the pattern on their fingers.
通過他們自己的卡片和編號  比如說 指紋圖案
Imagine how quickly we could find them  if they committed a crime.
想想看 如果他們犯了罪  我們可以多麼迅速地抓到他們
It's all very impressive, John.
這一切都太棒了 約翰
Well, would you like to stay here  or would you like to go somewhere else?
你想要繼續呆在這裡  還是想去別的地方？
It's up to you.
由你決定
Mr. Hoover.
胡佛先生
I'm not sure where you think  this is headed.
我不確定你想讓事情如何發展
Right, of course.
噢 當然
Miss Gandy.
甘迪小姐
I know we've only known each other  a brief time...
我知道我們倆只是認識了很短的時間
...but you would  make the finest of companions.
但我肯定你會是最好的伴侶
Your strength, your character,  your education.
你的力量 人格  還有教育
Are you poking fun at me?
你是在取笑我嗎？
No. No, no, no. No, no, of course not.
不 不 不 不 當然不是
Then please, Mr. Hoover, stand up.
那胡佛先生 請站起來說吧
I'd appreciate it  if you wouldn't share this...
我會非常感激  假如你不會把這些...
...with any of the other women  in the typing pool.
告訴任何你的打字員同事
No, of course not.
當然不會
All right. May I ask what... What...
好吧  能否問問...
What particular flaw  you seem to find in my character?
你覺得我的人格有什麼缺陷嗎？
No. We just met.
不 我們才剛認識
Right, of course.
當然
But I believe that I am a fast  and accurate judge of character.
但我相信我在判斷人格方面  又快又準
We've gone out three times,  but I don't need more.
我們已經約會三次  但我已不需要更多了
Most people do, but I don't.  I see people right off for what they are.
大多數人還需要 但我不用  我能一眼看穿別人是怎樣的人
And please, call me Edgar.  It's what my mother uses.
還有 請叫我埃德加  我母親就是這樣叫我
- Edgar?  - Yes?
- 埃德加？  - 嗯
Can you keep a secret?
你能保守一個秘密嗎？
Yes. Of course. You have my word.
當然 說到做到
I'm not interested in getting married.  My work comes first.
我對結婚沒有興趣  工作才是第一位
Hmm.
嗯...
Then perhaps you would consider  a position as my personal secretary.
那或許你可以考慮  做我的私人秘書
Yes.
好的
Shall we?
我們走吧？
The book.
那本書
Right.
對
After you.
你先請
I helped organize that library  just as I did this Bureau.
我正如那個圖書館一樣  規整了調查局
And many said we didn't need either.
很多人說其實二者都不需要這樣做
You see, innovators  aren't often celebrated.
你看 創新者總是不受待見
Not at first.
那只是一開始不受待見
Miss Gandy.
甘迪小姐
The nitwit Kennedy child  rang his baby buzzer again.
肯尼迪家那個蠢孩子  又呼我了
Perhaps he'd like a fresh diaper.
或許他需要換尿布了吧
Should I find out what  the Attorney General needs?
我是不是該看看總檢察長  需要些什麼？
No, I want the completed transcripts  of the Los Angeles recordings.
不 我需要洛杉磯那邊錄音的  完全副本
When I receive those,  then we'll answer his buzzer.
我收到了那些以後  才會回復他的呼叫
Very good.
很好
Edgar, Agent Smith is back.
埃德加 史密斯調查員回來了
He, uh, has some questions  about the Palmer Raids.
他對於帕爾默襲擊案還有些問題
Should I tell him to go?
我讓他走？
Helen, do you like him?
海倫 你喜歡他嗎？
I don't have an opinion of him yet.
我對他還沒有什麼看法
Hmm.
嗯...
Well, I like him. I trust him.
我喜歡他  我信任他
- I'll set him up in your outer office.  - No. No, no, no.
- 那我把他安排到你外面的辦公室  - 不 不 不
Bring him a desk in here.
搬個桌子讓他到裡面來
But in 1920,  how could I protect us from anyone?
但是在1920年  我該如何保護我們機構不受任何人影響？
Before I moved to this office,  we were powerless.
我搬來這個辦公室之前  我們毫無權力
We had few federal laws,  no right to carry firearms...
我們受制幾條聯邦法律  無權攜帶軍火...
...and Congress liked it that way.
國會也喜歡這樣
Criminals ran free, but there was no law  against keeping track of them...
犯罪者被釋放  但也沒有法律禁制我們追蹤他們
...so I made a decision on my own.
所以我自己做了個決定
I compiled note cards  and over five thousand names...
我彙編了超過5000個名字的卡片
...and called the one department  in Washington...
然後聯繫了華盛頓的一個部門...
...that still held a small piece  of untested power.
他們仍有一小部分  未經檢驗的權力
Was that the Department of Labor?  The power to deport, sir?
是勞工部嗎？  是不是他們有驅逐出境的權利？
But only to deport those  who checked two boxes.
但他們只驅逐  滿足以下兩個條件的人
They had to be foreign citizens and they  had to be working to harm our country.
必須是外國人  必須是他們的工作會損害我們國家的利益
And they cooperated with you?
他們和您合作了嗎？
Of course not.
當然沒有
No one freely shares power  in Washington, D.C., Agent Smith.
在華盛頓 沒人會就這樣跟你  分享他們的權力 史密斯調查員
There is no law  under which you can issue a warrant...
你還是沒有可依據的法律  來授權...
...for the arrest of an alien...
來逮捕一個外國人...
...when I have certified that  he is subject to deportation?
而我已經證明了他可以被驅逐出境
Without any evidence,  Mr. Attorney General, no.
沒有任何證據的情況下  不行 檢察官
- There exists a due process of law.  - Due process of law?
- 應該遵循正當法律程序  - 正當法律程序？
- What about the threat?  - There might be a threat...
- 他們對我們國家有威脅啊？  - 或許是有...
Might be?
或許？
Fine. There is a threat to our country.
好吧 確實對我們國家有威脅
But with no proof of a crime,  there's no cause for deportation.
但沒有犯罪的證據  我們就沒有理由將其驅逐出境
We'll see about that.
走著瞧吧
You'll be hearing from me.
我會聯繫你的
But one of their heads was a Mr. Caminetti.
但他們的領導之一是  卡密內蒂先生
He was weary of our Justice Department,  but he hated one person even more.
他厭煩了我們的司法部  但他更加討厭的是另一個人
I am a revolutionist by nature...
我是個天生的革命家...
...and as such...
在這裡
...l claim the right to rebel  and resist invasion...
我要呼籲反對和抵抗  侵略的權利
...by all means, force included.
使用一切手段 包括暴力
Emma Goldman. She was the hero  of the radical movement.
艾瑪·古德曼  她是激進運動的英雄人物
If I could hand Caminetti Emma Goldman,  he would deport her without a thought.
如果我們可以把她交給卡密內蒂  他會毫不猶豫地將她驅逐出境
But she was a citizen.
但她是美國公民
Would you like to stop, sir?
您需要休息一下嗎？
No.
不
I know it's hard for you to imagine today,  but there was a time...
我知道今天的你想像這些很難  但曾經...
...when the average American feared  for their safety and survival, Agent Smith.
普通的美國公民會擔心  他們的安全和生活 史密斯調查員
In Chicago, a coal strike started  by communist labor shut off all the power.
在芝加哥 由共產主義勞工發起的  煤礦罷工造成了大面積停電
Riots followed.
接著就是騷亂
And on Armistice Day  in Centralia, Washington...
然後在停戰紀念日那天  華盛頓州的森特勒利亞...
...veterans fresh back from the war  were murdered by radicals.
剛從戰場載譽歸來的老兵  被激進主義分子暗殺
The red revolution had arrived on our soil.
紅色革命的火焰  已經蔓延到了我們國家
No, no. We can't take them down  one by one.
不 我們不能逐個擊破
They'll go underground and we'll have  a bomb inside every senator's mailbox.
那樣他們會轉移到地下  那每個參議員的信箱裡都會有炸彈的危險
We need to have a simultaneous raid,  hitting all of them at once.
我們需要同一時間的突襲  把他們一網打盡
- Who are "they"?  - You're here to find out.
- 「他們」又是誰？  - 你就是來解決這個問題的
Now listen, I want a card on every  radical person in this country.
聽著 我需要我們國家每個激進分子  都有一張卡片來代表
Against the wall, gentlemen.
靠牆放 先生們
I wanna know who, where they're from,  what group, what they say.
我要知道他們是誰 從哪裡來  隸屬什麼組織 有什麼計劃
Who have already committed crimes?
那些已經有犯罪記錄的人？
I care more whether they intend to.  Against the wall, gentlemen, thank you.
我更關心的是他們是否有犯罪的打算  請靠牆放 謝謝
- How many are on our team?  - Only you four for now.
- 我們有多少人？  - 現在只有你們四個
I'll have locks installed.
我會把鎖安上
No, Miss Gandy.  That would bring too much attention.
不 甘迪小姐  那會吸引過多的注意
Nothing is to be alphabetically ordered.
任何東西都不許按字母順序排列
I want the cards to be broken down  into subjects and categories.
我要這些卡片以主題和類型分類
Now, this system should be easy enough  if explained.
這個系統應該簡潔明瞭
If not, finding information  should prove impossible.
如果不是  找到特定的信息就變得沒有可能
And trust no one,  not even our fellow agents.
不要相信任何人  甚至我們的同事探員
Half our colleagues are on both sides  of the payroll.
這裡半數的工作人員  還另有兼職
But the crimes we're investigating  aren't crimes, they're ideas.
但我們調查的犯罪並不是犯罪  只是犯罪的想法
Well, if your idea...
如果你的這個想法...
Against the wall, gentlemen. Thank you.
靠牆放 謝謝
If your idea is to come into our country  and plot the overthrow of our government...
假如你的想法是來我們國家  圖謀推翻政權...
...then, yes, indeed, that is a crime.
那麼當然 這就是犯罪
Mrs. Goldman married a U.S. citizen.
古德曼女士嫁給了一位美國公民
The man she married hasn't visited  her once in prison, yet this man...
她嫁給的這個男人從未探監過她  但是這個男人...
...the man she's lived with since her  wedding, he visits nightly.
自從婚禮以來就一直和此人同居的  他每晚都拜訪
What happens when  we raid this list of yours and find nothing?
假如你突襲了這群人  但毫無斬獲呢？
No guns, no bombs,  just innocent people deported.
沒有槍支 沒有炸彈  只是驅逐了無辜的人
From every corner of this nation,  the American people...
這個國家的每個角落  都有美國公民...
...have urged the Attorney General  to do something about this...
敦促總檢察長有所行動
...and return the United States  back to peace.
還美國一份和平
Now, I'm happy to send your objections  to Mr. Palmer himself...
現在我很樂意向帕爾默先生  傳達你的異議
...but, in the meantime,  expose Miss Goldman's sham marriage...
但同時  要揭發古德曼小姐令人不齒的婚姻
...and you will change that suit of yours.
你還得把你的衣服給換了
- Pardon me, John?  - Your suit, sir, your suit.
- 你說什麼 約翰？  - 你的西服
This isn't a saloon.
這裡不是酒吧
Have respect for yourself,  but, more importantly...
要尊重自己  更重要的是...
...have respect for this department.
尊重我們部門
Miss Gandy?
甘迪小姐？
Miss Goldman, are you an anarchist?
古德曼小姐  你是否是無政府主義者？
I decline to answer.
我拒絕回答
Do you deny that you are an anarchist?
那麼你否認自己是無政府主義者？
I decline to answer.
我拒絕回答
Do you believe in the overthrow  of the government of the United States?
你是否堅信應該推翻  美國政府的統治？
I refuse to answer.
我拒絕回答
Do you advocate the assassination  of public officials?
你是否主張  暗殺公共官員？
I refuse to answer.
我拒絕回答
This alien has refused to answer questions  pertaining to the charges in the warrant...
這位外國公民拒絕回答任何  這份法庭令中要求的問題
...notwithstanding the fact that  every opportunity was afforded her.
雖然我們已經給了她一切機會
I recommend deportation.
我的提議是驅逐出境
And just like that, we had our precedent.
就這樣 我們有了一個先例
Edgar, should I arrange our travel  to Paterson on Valentine's Day?
埃德加 我現在安排一下  情人節我們去帕特森的出行？
Yes, of course, Miss Gandy.
當然 甘迪小姐
I took the train to Paterson,  New Jersey, on February 14th.
2月14日 我乘坐火車  去了新澤西州的帕特森
If I could catch these radicals red-handed...
如果我能抓住這些激進分子  哪怕他們只是犯了輕罪
...then the Labor Department would have  to put them all on boats back home.
勞工部就必須把他們送上  回家的客船
So agents of the Bureau,  alongside local police...
所以調查局的探員們  還有當地警力...
...began raiding gathering places  of known communist radicals...
開始在已知有共產主義激進分子的地方  集聚起來準備突襲
...all across this country.
全國上下都是
These people are armed and violent.
這些人持械 行為暴力
They're prepared to kill to avoid capture.
這些人為了拘捕可以大開殺戒
Take one. Go on.
拿一支 去吧
- Are we allowed to use these, sir?  - These are gifts.
- 我們允許用這個嗎？  - 這些算是禮物
There is no law that prevents us  from using our own weapons.
沒有法律可以阻止我們使用自己的武器
Gentlemen, grab your guns.
先生們 拿好自己的槍
Gentlemen, quickly.
動作快
Let's move.
行動
Police! This is a raid!
警察！這是突擊檢查！
He's going for the window, stop him!
他要從窗子逃走了  快阻止！
That's enough!
夠了！
The leaflets matched exactly.
傳單內容完全吻合
We'd solved the bombings.
我們破了爆炸案
And, in the end, we arrested nearly  4000 communist radicals...
最終 我們逮捕了將近  4000名共產主義激進分子
...and deported over 500 of them.
驅逐出境了500多人
It was accomplished against great odds  and at great personal peril.
任務完成得很靠運氣  也冒著巨大的個人風險
They found the counterfeiting press,  five pistols, two automatics.
他們發現了假冒的記者  五支手槍 兩支自動槍
And in Trenton, they found gunpowder,  copper, brass wire, and batteries.
在特雷敦 他們找到了火藥  銅 銅絲 還有電池
- A bomb factory.  - Yes.
- 一個軍工廠  - 是
One hundred and twenty arrests in Detroit,  41 in Philadelphia, and 17 here so far.
底特律逮捕了120人  費城有41人 這裡目前有17人
But everyone in the Bureau involved  lost theirjob, correct?
但調查局裡和此事有關的人  都丟了飯碗 是嗎？
Even Palmer himself?
甚至帕爾默他自己？
Some did, and there's the lesson.
有些確實 但也算是教訓
You see, the bombs stopped,  and peace came.
你可以看到 爆炸案停止了  恢復了和平
The American people had forgotten  there ever was a threat.
美國人民逐漸忘記了  曾經有如此一種威脅
So when political adversaries  attacked Palmer...
所以當政治對手們  攻擊帕爾默的時候...
...for trying to protect this nation  from communism...
聲稱保護國家不受共產主義侵蝕...
...our countrymen allowed it to happen.
我們的同胞們就這樣熟視無睹
Because like today, they've forgotten  the bombs, the blood, the fear.
因為就像今天 他們已經忘記了  那些炸彈 那些流血犧牲 那些恐懼
But why Palmer and not you,  if you orchestrated the raids?
但為什麼是帕爾默而不是你  因為其實是你安排了那些突襲
I was 24 years old, Agent Smith.  I was just following orders.
我當時只有24歲  只是服從命令
I understand, sir.
我明白
And if we hadn't, you may very well  have been born into a communist state...
如果沒有這次行動  你很有可能就出生在一個共產主義的國家
...rather than the country you love today.
而不是你今天如此熱愛的祖國
- Am I right?  - Of course, sir.
- 我說的對嗎？  - 當然
Hmm.
嗯
Edgar?
埃德加？
Ignore him.
別管他
Edgar?
埃德加？
I am in a meeting, Mr. Tolson.  I'll be out in a moment.
我正在開會 托爾森  馬上就出去
Don't forget about your appointment  with the Attorney General, Edgar.
不要忘記跟檢察官的會面 埃德加
Files are not yet completed, Mr. Tolson.  Please go away.
文件還沒準備好 托爾森  你走吧
Thank you.
謝謝
Thank you, sir. I apologize.  I'll finish this chapter tonight.
謝謝您 抱歉  我今晚就會寫好這一章
Very well, Agent Smith.
很好 史密斯調查員
In the Academy, do they tell the story  of how I got here?
在學校 他們有提起  我是如何做到這個位置的嗎？
Yes, sir. Uh, you were called into  the new Attorney General's office...
是的 你被新的檢察官  叫到他的辦公室...
- Harlan Fiske Stone.  - Yes, sir, Attorney General Stone.
- 哈蘭·菲斯克·斯通  - 是的，斯通總檢察長
He called you into his office  and told you to sit down, sir.
他讓你去他的辦公室  讓你坐下
Sir, there are over a dozen vacancies  in Chicago.
芝加哥有十多個空缺職位
And with the robbery rates rising,  it would profit the Bureau...
搶劫率正在攀升  或許對調查局有利的是...
...to start filling vacancies  and make recoveries.
我們開始填補這些空缺  努力復甦
I have files on potential suspects,  and with a congressional hearing...
我有整理潛在犯罪嫌疑人的資料  經過國會的聽證會...
Lower the treble, son. You didn't call  this meeting, I did. Sit down.
別激動 孩子  不是你叫我來開會的 是我叫你 坐下吧
Yes, sir.
是
Everyone you've worked with here is gone.  And there's a reason for that.
這裡每個和你共事過的人都離開了  而且事出有因
This Bureau is of exceedingly bad odor.  Would you agree?
調查局充斥著惡劣的氛圍  你也同意吧？
Yes, sir.
是的
And, no offense,  you seem to have no social life.
並無冒犯之意  你似乎也沒有什麼社交
No wife, no girlfriend.  As far as I can tell, no pals at all.
沒有老婆 沒有女友  據我所知 甚至朋友都沒有
That is accurate, sir.
確實是這樣
And you're shamelessly distracted  by this hodgepodge fingerprinting affair.
你還旁若無人地癡迷著  那亂七八糟的指紋系統
Sir, it wouldn't be hodgepodge if we could  centralize the prints here, I assure you.
假如我們可以將所有指紋都集中到這裡  這絕不會是亂七八糟的事 我可以保證
It's a speculative science at best.
這最多也就是一種投機學
Yes, sir.
是的
And why do they call you Speed?
他們為什麼都叫你「飛毛腿」？
Who calls me that?
誰這麼叫我了？
They all do, behind your back, evidently.
他們都這樣  不過很明顯是在你背後
I gained a reputation for delivering  groceries when I was 10 years old.
我10歲的時候給雜貨店送外賣  積攢了這個名聲
I was the fastest in the neighborhood.  It was just a nickname.
我在我們街坊是速度最快的  這只是個外號
You sure it's not for the way you talk?
你確定他們不是在說你說話的方式？
Perhaps, sir.
大概吧
Young man, I want you to be acting  director of the Bureau of investigation.
年輕人 我希望你出任  調查局的局長
I will take the job, Mr. Stone,  but only on certain conditions.
我會接受這個職務 斯通先生  但有一些條件
What are they?
什麼條件？
The Bureau must be divorced from politics  and not be a catchall for political hacks.
這個調查局必須和政治獨立開  不能成為政治的代言人
Recruits must be college-educated.
新人必須有大學文憑
Appointments must be based on merit.
任用的人必須體面
Promotions will be made on proven ability.
得到升職的人必須有嫻熟的工作能力
And, well, the Bureau will be  responsible only to you, sir...
還有 這個調查局僅由您一人負責
...the Attorney General.
總檢察長
I wouldn't give you the job  under any other conditions.
換做其他條件  我也不會給你這份工作
That's all. Good day.
就這樣了 日安
Well, thank you, sir.
謝謝您
I am determined to summarily dismiss  from this Bureau...
我已決定  會從調查局剔除那些...
...any employee whom I find  indulging in the use of intoxicants.
沉迷於酒精的人
It is my belief that when a man  becomes a part of this Bureau...
我相信  當一個人成為調查局的一份子...
...he must so conduct himself,  both officially and unofficially...
他必須規範自己的行為  不管官方還是非官方
...as to eliminate even  the slightest possibility of criticism...
以消除可能存在的  哪怕最小的批判聲
...as to his conduct.
批判他品行的聲音
- And what is your name, sir?  - Agent Williams, sir.
- 你叫什麼名字？  - 威廉姆斯 先生
- Pleasure to meet you, Agent Williams.  - You too, sir.
- 很高興見到你 威廉姆斯探員  - 您也是
And your name?
你的名字呢？
Agent Caffrey, sir.
卡福利探員
- Your assignment?  - I'm headed to Kansas City...
- 你的任務是？  - 我正要前往堪薩斯城
...to aid in the search  for bank robber Frank Nash, sir.
協助調查銀行搶劫犯弗蘭克·納什
Mm, that is dangerous work,  and when you return...
這是一項危險的任務  你回來以後...
...you will be rewarded for your service.
你會因你的努力工作得到嘉獎
You still fancy facial hair, Agent Stokes?
斯托克斯探員  你還是很喜歡留鬍子嘛？
- The ladies appreciate it.  - Hmm.
- 女士們喜歡  - 嗯
And I suppose the ladies' opinions  are more important than the Bureau's?
那我是不是可以認為  女士們的意見比調查局的意見更重要？
No.
不
Sir.
長官
Perhaps you are better suited  for the police force...
或許你在警察局工作更合適...
...than the Bureau of investigations.
相比在調查局
I've been with the Department and  the Bureau for seven years.
我已經為司法部和調查局效力了7年
Almost as long as you.
幾乎跟你一樣長時間
No.
不
You were with the old Bureau seven years,  and that Bureau is now gone, sir.
你在舊的調查局工作了7年  那個舊的已經不復存在了
And so are you.
你也是一樣
I quickly dismissed all agents
我很快就解雇了所有  不符合我要求的探員
Education, physical fitness...
教育背景 身體條件...
...but, above all, loyalty.
最重要的是 忠誠
I've had two made.  Same cut, different pattern.
我做了兩套  一樣的裁剪 不同花紋
And two suits for you.  They'll be delivered on Friday.
還有給你的兩套西裝  禮拜五就送來了
Thank you, Mother.
謝謝 母親
It's platinum...
這是鉑金的...
...six diamonds and a star sapphire.
六顆鑽石  一顆星光藍寶石
- Heh.  - It's absolutely beautiful, Mother.
真是太美了 母親
Thank you.
謝謝
I've told the whole neighborhood  about you. They all know.
我跟整個街坊鄰居都說起了你  他們都知道了
No, I shouldn't,  I've been gaining weight, Mother.
不 我不該吃  我已經在增重了
It's solid weight. There's nothing wrong  with solid weight on a man.
那是結實的體重  一個男人結結實實長點肉沒錯
- All right.  - I'm so incredibly proud of you, Edgar.
- 好吧  - 我真是太為你驕傲了 埃德加
I'm starting an album for you.
我開始為你做一個冊子了
I'm gonna put everything in it.  This is just the beginning.
我會把所有材料都收集進去  這只是個開始
"Johnny Hoover appointed acting director  of the Bureau of investigations."
「約翰·胡佛被任命為  調查局的局長」
Can you read that?
你能讀讀這個嗎？
You proud of your uncle?
為叔叔自豪嗎？
Gentlemen.
先生們
I want to introduce you. Come with me.
我想介紹一下你  跟我來
Edgar, good to see you.
埃德加 很高興見到你
Good to see you, Lawrence.
很高興見到你 勞倫斯
I'd like to introduce you  to Mr. Clyde Tolson.
我想向你介紹克萊德·托爾森先生
Graduated from George Washington  University tonight with a law degree.
今晚剛從喬治華盛頓大學的法學院畢業
Hmm.
嗯
Congratulations, Mr. Tolson.
祝賀你 托爾森先生
Thank you, Mr. Hoover. I believe you are  one of our most distinguished alumni.
謝謝你 胡佛先生  我想你應該是我校最傑出的校友之一了
I did, yes. L, uh, do have a degree  from the school, yes.
噢 是的  我確實是從同個學校畢業的
I was admiring your suit, Mr. Tolson.  You should take a lesson, Lawrence.
我很喜歡你的西服 托爾森先生  羅倫斯 你該學著點
Thank you, sir. It's a custom cut,  from Garfinkel's department store.
謝謝 這是在加芬克爾百貨商店定制的
Ah.
這樣
Do you have a card, Mr. Tolson?
你有名片嗎 托爾森先生？
I do, yes, of course.
當然 我有
Here you go.
這是我的
Good to see you, Lawrence.
很高興見到你 勞倫斯
Thank you, sir.
謝謝您
"Well-educated, highly recommended,  willing to guarantee five years service.
「良好的教育，被高度推薦  可以保證五年的工作時間」
Has a family in New York  and a new baby."
「家人在紐約 有剛出生的孩子」
No interview.
這個不用面試
The family in New York or the baby?
是因為紐約的家人還是剛出生的孩子？
Miss Gandy, five years is not enough.  We need men willing to dedicate their lives.
甘迪小姐 五年是不夠的  我們需要一個願意奉獻一生的人
How many is that so far?
現在有多少個了？
- That's 320 denied and 21 interviews.  - Hmm.
- 320個被拒 21個面試者  - 嗯
Did we receive an application  from a Mr. Tolson?
我們有收到一份  來自托爾森先生的申請嗎？
Yes.
有
Yes, his report states  he has confidence, poise...
這裡 他的報告陳述道  他自信 優雅...
...his diction is excellent.
用詞精準
But although physically fitted for it,  might be displeased with rugged work.
雖然身體條件沒問題  但並不希望做棘手的工作
His only interest is to gain experience  that would benefit a private law practice.
他只是想為自己的個人法律實踐  積攢一些經驗
And he has no interest in being here  for any period of time...
他也沒有說起  願意在這裡工作多長時間...
...which would render  employment speculative.
那只會讓就業更加投機
Hmm.
恩
He did receive  a letter of recommendation...
他有一封推薦信...
...from the executive assistant  of the Secretary of War.
來自戰爭部長的行政助理
That's fantastic, Miss Gandy.
這很好嘛
Yes. It mentions here that Mr. Tolson  showed no particular interest in women.
信裡提到托爾森先生...  對女人沒有特別的興趣
Then again, some of our best agents excel  because they have no family encumbrance.
再一次地 我們最好的一些探員  之所以如此優秀 是因為他們沒有家庭的負擔
Yes, you're right. Set up an interview.
是的 你是對的  安排面試
You know what the problem is,  Miss Gandy?
你知道問題是什麼嗎  甘迪？
These men, they don't...  They don't look up to me.
這些人 他們並不...  並不崇拜我
Of course they do.
他們當然崇拜你
I don't mean figuratively.  I mean they don't look up to me.
我這並不是比喻  我就是說 他們不崇拜我
Well, if you could conduct the entire  interview from behind your desk...
假如你可以坐在桌子後面  來進行面試...
...instead of walking about the office,  I could correct that.
而不是在辦公室走來走去  我可以讓他們崇拜你
Indeed.
那確實是
Miss Gandy, suppose I had information  on someone in a position of power...
甘迪 假如我有某位當權人士的  秘密資料...
...harmful information.
有害的信息
It goes against my nature  to destroy such information...
毀滅這些資料有悖我的意圖...
...but I don't trust it  in the general files either.
但我也不放心放在一般的資料一起
Could I trust it with you?
我能拜託你嗎？
If we were to create a confidential file?
我們或許可以保存一些絕密資料？
Of course, Edgar.
當然 埃德加
Thank you, Miss Gandy.
謝謝你 甘迪
Information is power.
信息就是力量
It protected us from the communists  in 1919...
信息保護我們1919年  不受共產主義分子危害
...and since has been vigilantly collected,  organized, and maintained by our FBl.
自那以後 就由聯邦調查局  小心地收集 整理  維護
Attorney General Kennedy's Office.
肯尼迪總檢察長辦公室
Did you always have this fireplace  or did you have it put in?
你一直都有這個壁爐嗎  還是後來安的？
It was put in.
後來安的
What were you doing with wiretaps  in that house?
你在那間屋子裝竊聽器是做什麼？
You asked that I pursue this  organized crime element, Mr. Kennedy...
是你讓我追查這些犯罪線索的  肯尼迪先生
...and I did so, sir, with diligence.
我也照做了  勤勤懇懇
- Do you use the fireplace?  - Rarely.
- 你會用這個壁爐嗎？  - 很少
Who else has heard the recording?
還有誰聽過這個錄音？
I have filed the matter  personal and confidential.
我已經將資料封為  個人的 高度機密的
I'm the only person with access to it.
只有我才能取得這些資料
Mr. Hoover, I asked you to pursue  a real threat.
胡佛先生 我是讓你追查  真正的威脅
Instead, you've publicly denied  the existence of organized crime...
相反地 你公然否認  有組織的犯罪的存在
...and now this gross display  of intimidation.
現在還有這重大的恐嚇
Mr. Attorney General,  I was only following orders.
檢察官  我只是服從命令
We bugged the basement of a home  in Los Angeles...
我們竊聽了洛杉磯  一幢房子的地下室
...that was a known gathering place  for lawbreakers.
那是一群違法犯罪者聚會的地方
How was I to know that an East German  communist would be down there...
我怎麼知道一個東德的共產主義分子  會在那裡...
...having sex with your brother,  the President of the United States?
會在那裡跟你的哥哥  也就是美國總統 上床？
Do not shoot the messenger, sir.  I am here to protect you both.
不要射殺那些探員  我是來保護你們倆的
Remember that.
記住這一點
What do you want from me?
你想讓我怎樣？
If this information were to go public...
如果這段資料公開...
...it would create widespread distrust  in your brother's leadership capabilities.
會造成對你們兄弟倆領導能力  大面積的質疑
And above all else, I hold the well-being  of our country paramount.
不僅這些  我還掌控我們國家最高的福利
So how may I help you, Mr. Hoover?
那我該怎麼做呢 胡佛先生？
Well, if I am to pursue the elements  that you consider a threat...
倘若我得幫你追查  你認為是威脅的東西
...l humbly request that you allow me  the same power and access...
我想要您允許我有同樣的權力...
...to follow the groups that I see  as an immediate threat.
來追查我認為有重大威脅的人
It's not 1920 anymore.
這已經不是1920年了
You know who Stanley Levinson is, sir?
你知道斯坦利·列維森是誰嗎？
A lawyer.
一個律師
A white, communist lawyer  organizing at the highest levels...
一個白人 共產主義律師  組織著最高層...
...including the SCLC.
包括南方基督教領袖會議
Now, their group is growing.
現在他們的群體正在壯大
They are entirely self-serving...
他們完全自給自足...
...and their leadership is openly critical  of this department here.
他們的領導權已經公然  危及到我們的部門
Did you read the memos that I sent?
你看了我發過來的備忘嗎？
No, no, I can't say that I have.
不 還沒有
It says right here, Mr. Kennedy.
肯尼迪先生 我在這裡寫了
They claim we are...
他們宣稱我們是...
..."unable to get convictions in even  the worst, most heinous crimes..."
「不能給哪怕最滔天最極惡的犯罪定罪」
...and that we have "faltered under  the pressure, complexities...
我們還「在壓力下動搖」
...and responsibilities of our office,"  in print.
「因為部門的複雜性和義務」  白紙黑字印出來
- Right here in "The Washington Post."  - You can't bear a little criticism?
- 就在這《華盛頓郵報》上  - 你就受不了一點點的批評？
Well, it depends on what their aim is.
這取決於批評的目的了
They are gaining considerable power.
他們正在聚集一股很客觀的力量
Their priorities are singularly focused  on their own issues.
他們有優先權  單單關注自己的事
They are trying to incite revolt.
他們在試圖煽動叛亂
Frankly, they sound more critical  of your office than mine.
顯然 他們看上去更多的批評你的部門  而不是我的
There's a new face to communism,  Edgar, and this isn't it.
共產主義有了新的局面了  埃德加 這件事不是的
Communism is a foreign threat now,  not domestic.
共產主義更多地是海外的威脅  不是國內的
Mr. Kennedy,  before you were even born...
肯尼迪先生  遠在你出生以前...
...l heard that very same argument  from a Mr. Mitchell Palmer.
我從一位叫米切爾·帕爾默先生口中  聽到了一模一樣的說辭
Do you know what it took  to change his mind?
你知道最後是什麼  讓他改變自己的想法嗎？
A bomb.
一枚炸彈
If he would have sat in his rocking chair  five more minutes in 1919...
假如他在1919年的那天  在他的椅子上多坐五分鐘
...we'd have been lucky enough  to find an intact index finger.
我們就只能發現他的手指頭了
Now, I do not want that to happen  to you or your brother, sir.
現在 我不想讓這些事  發生在你和你哥哥身上
There's no reason  we both can't get what we want.
沒理由  讓我們都得不到我們想要的
We can wage a war on two fronts, sir.  You understand?
我們可以在兩個前線都發動戰爭  你明白我的意思嗎？
You can go now, Mr. Hoover.
你可以走了 胡佛先生
Yes, sir.
是
Please leave the transcripts here with me.
把副本留下給我
Yes, sir.
是
Oh, and feel free and share them  with your brother.
噢 也可以讓你哥哥看看這些
Oh, and let him know that I have  a copy of my own in safekeeping.
讓他知道  我自己也留了一份存檔
- Unh.  - Your 4:00 is here, sir.
您4點的面試者到了
Thank you, Miss Gandy.  Send him right in, thank you.
謝謝你 甘迪  讓他進來吧
Please, have a seat, Mr. Tolson.
請坐吧 托爾森先生
- Mr. Hoover, thank you for this opportunity.  - Yes. Please.
- 胡佛先生 謝謝您給我這次機會  - 請吧
- Have a seat.  - Thank you, sir.
- 請坐  - 謝謝
There were several problems  with your application, Mr. Tolson...
你的申請材料有幾個問題  托爾森先生
...not the least of which is the fact  that you did not show...
且不提其實你並不...
...the proper requirement to the Bureau...
符合調查局的條件...
...nor the proper dedication  to protecting the American people...
也沒有要保護美國人民的忠心...
...and the American way.
以美國自己的方式
May I remind you  that this is not a platform...
我必須告訴你的是
...to a fatter paycheck in private practice,  Mr. Tolson?
這裡不是給你的個人法律實踐  發工資的地方 托爾森先生
Is there something the matter,  Mr. Tolson?
有什麼問題嗎 托爾森先生？
No, sir.
不
Ls exercise a requirement  for all agents, sir?
這鍛煉是所有探員都要求的嗎？
Yes. All our agents need to be  in top physical condition.
是的 我們所有的探員  都需要有最好的身體條件
We must outsmart and outmatch  the public enemy at every turn.
我們必須對公眾之敵百發百中
Yes, of course.
當然
So, uh, what routine do you do, sir?
所以您經常做什麼來健身？
Push-ups, sit-ups, and squatting.
俯臥撐 仰臥起坐 還有下蹲運動
I see.
這樣
Would you like me to fix the curtain?
我來幫你整理一下窗簾吧？
Or perhaps I could open a window.
或許可以開點窗
I always prefer  a little bit of air after exercise.
運動之後我喜歡來一些新鮮空氣
Don't you?
你呢？
If it would please you.
如果你喜歡的話
And, sir, where I may fall short  in terms of resume...
我或許在簡歷方面不如他人...
...l apparently far exceed  the rest in terms of honesty.
但其他方面  我的忠誠度遠遠超過他們
I didn't lie to get this appointment, sir.
我並未因為這個工作而說謊
Like the rest, yes,  I would like to start a practice...
不像其他人  是的 我希望做法律實踐...
...but I could be persuaded otherwise  if the right opportunities were to arise.
但我也可以做其他事  倘若有不錯的機會
Hmm.
嗯
Fair enough, Mr. Tolson.
有道理 托爾森先生
Fair enough.
有道理
These sleeves seem to be  the correct length.
這袖子看上去長度正好
I found you two tie options.
我找到兩條領帶給你選
This one is a bit more fashion-forward...
這條更加時髦...
...but it would complement this suit  and cut and fabric.
更好的搭配這套西服  包括剪裁和材質
It's too loud, don't you think?
你不覺得有點太扎眼嗎？
Too loud? Okay, which is why  I found this one, the backup.
太扎眼？好吧  所以我還給你找了個後備
- It's a bit more directorial, a little bit more...  - It's a little bit more reserved, I agree.
- 這條更有領導人氣質 更...  - 更含蓄些 我同意
Let's keep this as a second option, please.  Thank you, Clyde.
我們留著這條作候補吧  謝謝你 克萊德
Are you Mr. John Hoover?
你是約翰·胡佛先生嗎？
I am. Is there a problem?
是我 有問題嗎？
It seems there's a Mr. John Hoover  whose credit has gone bad with us.
似乎有位約翰·胡佛先生  在我們這裡信用度很差
That would appear to be you.
看上去就是你了
That is not me, sir, on my word.
肯定不是我 我保證
My mother calls me Edgar, my niece calls  me J.E., and I sign John E., not John.
我母親叫我埃德加 我侄女叫我J.E.  我簽名都簽約翰·E 而不是約翰
Well, sir, if you're a friend  of Mr. Tolson's...
假如您是托爾森先生的朋友...
...just choose one name and reapply.
就再選一個名字 重新申請一次
All right.
好吧
Thank you very much.
非常感謝
Morning, Miss Gandy.
早上好 甘迪小姐
What? You don't like it?
怎麼？你不喜歡嗎？
Mr. Hoover,  there's been a massacre in Kansas City.
胡佛先生  堪薩斯城發生了一起慘案
One of our own?
有我們自己的人？
Special Agent Caffrey?
卡福利探員？
Let him have it!
讓他來！
By 1930, the communist threat  had been beaten back...
1930年 共產主義分子危機捲土重來
...but the Depression had hit  and there was a new threat.
但同時有大蕭條的影響  產生新的威脅
The bank robber, the car thief,  and the kidnapper.
銀行搶劫 盜車 綁架
But, unfortunately, as with communism,  America didn't react with scorn.
但不幸的是 對於共產主義  美國並未打壓
They gave the American gangster  admiration.
他們激發出了美國黑幫
And the defiance by desperate,  armed criminals...
這些窮凶極惡的 持械的犯罪分子
...of the forces of society and civilization  can no longer be ignored.
對社會和文明力量的挑戰  不會再得到縱容
Bugs Moran and Al Capone  top the list of public enemies.
「瘋狂莫蘭」和阿爾·卡彭是我們的頭號公敵  （前者是禁酒令時期芝加哥的黑幫 後者是意大利裔美國黑幫）
Look around you.  They could be anywhere.
看看你們周圍  他們無處不在
May I remind you that the Bureau of  Investigation seeks to be your protector.
我必須重申  調查局會是大家的保護傘
It belongs to you. It is as close to you  as your nearest telephone.
它屬於人民  它就和家裡的電話一樣就在你們身邊
And with your help...
有了你們的幫助...
Warner Bros. Presents
華納兄弟影業為大家呈現有聲電影
"The Public Enemy."
James Cagney plays  public enemy number one.
詹姆斯·卡格尼飾演頭號公敵
- Why, you.  - Aah!
- 為什麼 你...  - 啊！
There you go with that wishing stuff again.
你又開始說那些願望了
Maybe you found someone  you like better.
或許你可以找到你更喜歡的人
Coming soon to your neighborhood theater.
即將登陸各大院線
Fantastic.
真棒
That summer, a single crime opened  the door to set things right.
那個夏天 一場犯罪  讓一切都步入了正軌
Do you know what that was, Mr. Jones?
你知道是哪件事嗎  瓊斯先生？
Sorry, sir, what was that?
抱歉 是什麼事？
Who is the most famous man  of the 20th Century thus far?
目前為止 誰是20世紀最有名的人？
Joe McCarthy, sir?
喬·麥卡錫？  （約瑟夫·雷蒙德·麥卡錫，美國政治家，反共產主義者）
Mr. McCarthy was an opportunist...
麥卡錫就是個機會主義者...
...not a patriot, Mr. Jones.
並不是個愛國者 瓊斯先生
Who is the most famous man  of the 20th Century thus far?
目前為止  誰是20世紀最有名的人？
The most famous?
最有名？
Ls that you, sir?
那是不是您？
Well, I suppose his notoriety  depends on the field that he is in.
我覺得他的惡名  取決於他是什麼行業的
His field was in the clouds.
天上飛的那種
Well, then Charles Lindbergh, sir.
那就是查爾斯·林德伯格了  （美國飛行員 首個單人不著陸飛越大西洋的人）
Yes?
喂？
Charles Lindbergh's  baby has been kidnapped from his home.
查爾斯·林德伯格的小孩  被人從家中綁架了
Send officers from Trenton.  I'll be on the first train.
從特雷敦派警官過去  我會乘頭班火車趕到
What is it?
什麼事？
Charles Lindbergh...  Lindbergh's baby's been kidnapped.
查爾斯·林德伯格...  他的孩子被綁架了
You've got to find him.
你得找到他
He has to be brought home alive.
你得把孩子安全帶回來
Yes, Mother.
是的 母親
Yes, Mother, I know.
是的 母親 我明白
When we arrived at  Mr. Lindbergh's home that morning in 1932...
當1932年的那個早晨  我們到達林德伯格家的時候
...we began an investigation that would  forever change our Bureau.
我們正開始一項  即將永遠改變調查局的案件
This morning we've heard from  the Pennsylvania Railroad, Will Rogers...
今天早上我們收到來自賓州鐵路的  威爾·羅傑斯的消息...
...President Hoover,  Governor Roosevelt, Customs...
胡佛總統 羅斯福州長 海關...
...the U.S. Mail, and the Boy Scouts.
還有美國郵政 和童子軍
All of you. Get off of that dirt.
你們所有人  趕緊離開那泥地
You're trampling evidence.  Immediately! Get off!
你們這是踩踏證據  快！走開！
There's nothing there. We checked.  No defined footprints.
那裡什麼都沒有 我們檢查過了  沒有可以辨認的腳印
It appears he was wearing fabric  on his shoes.
似乎罪犯在鞋子上綁了布
You don't think the size  could've held some value?
那你不覺得印記的大小  也會有點價值嗎？
How did he get up there? Are there  marks on the window and wall as well?
他是怎麼爬上去的？  窗子和牆上是不是也有證據？
A ladder.  We found it 100 yards away.
我們在100碼之外發現了梯子
We moved it inside.
我們把它放進去了
You moved it?
你動過它了？
Yes, for safekeeping.
是啊 安全保管起見
Congratulations, Mr. Schwarzkopf.  You have contaminated the crime scene.
恭喜你啊 施瓦茲科夫先生  你徹徹底底污染了這個犯罪現場
Now, get your boots off this property.
你現在可以高抬貴腳趕緊走了
And what right do you have  to be here, Mister, uh...?
你有什麼權利來這裡？  你叫...
J. Edgar Hoover,  director of the Bureau of investigation.
J·埃德加·胡佛  調查局局長
We've been sent by President Hoover  to ensure the investigation...
我們由胡佛總統指派  來保障這次調查
The president has authorized access  to all documents and evidence.
總統已經授權我們可以  查看所有的文件和證據
Mr. Hoover, you're free to observe,  but New Jersey's not the president's domain.
胡佛先生 你看看沒問題  但新澤西可不是總統的私人領土
And where is Mr. Lindbergh?  I'd like to hear his opinion on the matter.
林德伯格先生呢？  我想要聽聽他的意見
- Mr. Lindbergh's around back.  - After you, sir.
- 林德伯格先生在後面  - 您先請
He's been up all night.
他一夜沒睡
Mr. Lindbergh himself  came down to meet me.
林德伯格先生親自下來見了我
He shook my hand and expressed his  gratitude and faith in our young Bureau.
他和我握手  表達了他對我們年輕的調查局的感謝和信任
He fell five feet.
他從五尺高的地方摔下來
Who did?
誰？
The kidnapper, with the child in his arms.
綁架犯  手裡還抱著孩子
That's speculation, Mr. Hoover.
這只是推測
Mr. Lindbergh, sir, if the ladder had split  while the person was on their way up...
林德伯格先生 倘若這個梯子在  這個人爬上去的時候已經開裂了
...it would have collapsed.  You see, it was a miscalculation.
它肯定已經塌了  你看 這是個失算
It was meant to bear the weight of a man,  but not the weight of a man and child.
它本來可以承受一個成人的重量爬上去  但無法承受一個成人加一個孩子爬下來
We have other theories.
我們有別的看法
Where's the ransom note?
要贖金的字條呢？
Of course.
在這
And you are touching that  with your bare hands as well?
你就這樣光著手摸這張紙？
We checked.
我們檢查過了
There are none of those finger imprints  that you fancy so valuable.
沒有你那麼喜歡的指紋在上面
Please hand it over, Mr. Schwarzkopf.
把它遞過來吧 施瓦茲科夫先生
That's Colonel Schwarzkopf.
我叫科內爾·施瓦茲科夫
"Have 50,000 dollars ready,"  spelled R-E-D-Y.
「準備好五萬美元」  ready（準備）拼成了R-E-D-Y
"We will inform you where,"  spelled W-E-R-E, "to deliver the money"...
「我們會告訴你地點」  拼成了W-E-R-E；「把錢送到...」
...spelled M-O-N-Y.
money（錢）拼成了M-O-N-Y
"We warn you for making anything public  or for notify the police.
「警告你不許聲張消息或者通知警方」
Indication for all letters are signature,"  S-I-N-G, "singnature."
「指示的所有信件都要簽字」  拼成了S-I-N-G，「singnature」
Three holes.
紙有三個孔
I want this letter and the ladder.
我想要這封信和那個梯子
No jurisdiction.  I've showed what you asked for.
你沒有這個管轄權  我們已經給你看了你想看的
- It's time for you to go.  - Mr. Lindbergh, please...
- 你可以走了  - 林德伯格先生 請...
Mr. Hoover, thank you. As you can see,  we have everything under control.
胡佛先生 謝謝你  你也看得到 一切都安排妥當
Thank you, gentlemen.
謝謝你們
Thank you for your time, Mr. Lindbergh.
謝謝你抽空 林德伯格先生
Clyde.
克萊德
Clyde, I'm afraid for his boy.
克萊德 我很擔心他的孩子
He trusts the local police more than us.
相比我們 他更信任當地警方
He thinks we're all fools.
他覺得我們都是傻子
He'll go around them too.  He's going to bargain with the kidnappers.
他也會聽他們的  他會去跟綁架犯談判
President Hoover called me the morning  the child was taken...
胡佛總統今天早上給我打電話  告訴我孩子被綁架了
...and asked me to do whatever was  in my power to solve this crime.
他讓我做我權力以內的任何事  去解決案件
But do you know what all the power  of the Bureau means...
但你們是否知道  調查局的所有權力是什麼？
...without federal laws, without arms,  without the ability to make arrests?
沒有法律保護 沒有槍支  沒有權利來逮捕？
It means nothing.
這什麼都不是
Mr. Chairman, I urge passage  of the Lindbergh Law...
主席 我強烈建議通過這項林德伯格法案
...making kidnapping a federal offense.
讓綁架成為一項國家級的罪行
To immediately deliver all the fingerprints  in this country to my office...
應當立即把國家所有的指紋  都送來我辦公室
...so that we may create a central file.
我們就可以建立一個中央檔案
To help arm our agents  so that they have a fighting chance...
把我們的探員武裝起來  讓他們有機會戰鬥...
...against the submachine guns of some  of the most dangerous characters...
和那些最危險的  持衝鋒鎗的人作戰
...in the history of American criminality.
美國歷史上最危險的罪犯之一
And I urge you to do this  in the name of Little Lindy.
我要敦促你們  為了小林迪這樣做
Because if he can be taken,  then what child is safe?
因為連他都可以被綁架  那誰家的孩子還會是安全的？
And if we cannot aid in his safe return,  then what use are we?
假如我們無法幫助他安全回家  那我們還有什麼用？
Every fingerprint from the local authorities...
從當地機關送來的指紋...
...across the country began flowing in.  Finally, we had a centralized system.
來自全國各地 開始湧來  最終 我們有了這個中央系統
What is it, Edgar?
怎麼了 埃德加？
The last of the fingerprints came in  from Chicago.
芝加哥送來的最後一批指紋
You know our new president has scheduled  a meeting with me, Miss Gandy?
你知道我們的新總統  跟我安排了一次見面吧
Do you know that there are talks  of reorganizing the Bureau?
你知不知道有謠言說  要重組調查局？
Yes, I've heard similar whispers.
是的我聽到了相似的傳言
Hmm.
嗯
Have you?
是嗎？
Miss Gandy, do you remember that file  we created on his wife?
甘迪 你還記不記得  我們給他的妻子建立的那個文件？
Mrs. Roosevelt?
羅斯福夫人？
Yes.
是的
Will you make a copy for me, please?
你能給我拷貝一份嗎？
Yes, of course.
是的 當然
Thank you, Miss Gandy.
謝謝你 甘迪
Lindbergh hired criminals to find his son.
林德伯格是讓一群罪犯來找他兒子
Off the desk now, Agent Garrison,  follow me.
可以離開桌子了 加裡森調查員  跟我來
Yes, sir.
是
He even got an offer from Al Capone  to help pay the ransom money...
他甚至得到了來自阿爾·卡彭的邀請  來幫他付贖金
...but, in the end, he employed an eccentric  by the name of John Condon...
但是最後 他雇了一個怪人  叫約翰·康登的
...who placed a newspaper ad to act  as a go-between with the kidnappers.
這個人在報紙上登廣告  以此跟綁架犯交流
Now, was Condon a criminal too?
那康登也是個罪犯嗎？
He most certainly wasn't  an agent of the law, Mr. Garrison.
他肯定也不是什麼法律的代言人
Why are you doing this?
你為什麼要這樣做？
So a mother may have her baby again.
這樣一個母親就能重新找回她的孩子
And you may know that the  American people are grateful...
你也可以知道  美國人民很感謝你...
...for the honor bestowed upon them  by your pluck and daring.
賜予他們膽量和氣魄
And how do we know the kidnapper is the  same that wrote the letters that you have?
那我們怎麼知道  綁架者與跟你寫這些信的是同一個人？
The symbol, uh, matches  the original letter's symbol, doesn't it?
有標記 跟原來的信一樣  不是嗎？
What is it, Mr. Lindbergh?
怎麼了 林德伯格先生？
In a moment of thoughtlessness...
有一次我很輕率地...
...l showed the symbol  to some other men...
我把那些標記給了其他人看
...and I'm not sure  that they were trustworthy.
我也不確定  他們是否值得信任了
I'm not sure anyone is trustworthy.
我不確定任何人是否值得信任了
I will be having your letters analyzed...
我會拿你收到的這些信去鑒定
...to make sure that they  are from the same author.
來確認他們是來自同一個人之手
And while Mr. Lindbergh  placed his faith in hoodlums...
正當林德伯格先生  把自己的信任交給這些惡棍的時候
...we began cultivating the one thing  criminals couldn't fight...
我們開始發展一件  讓罪犯無法戰勝的事
...with all the guns in the world.
用世上任何槍都不行
Gentlemen, please leave this room.  Clear all these tables. Time to go, now.
先生們 請離開這個房間  清理桌面 現在開始
Where can we smoke, sir?
那我們去哪裡抽煙？
Not my concern. Out of my sight.
不關我的事  別在我面前
- Mr. Osborne, tell us what you need.  - Uh, bright lights, a microscope...
- 奧斯本先生 告訴我們你的需要  - 明亮的燈光 一個顯微鏡...
...measuring instruments,  magnifying glasses. A, uh, projector.
度量工具 放大鏡  還有一個投影儀
You have the full resources of the Bureau.  Don't be shy.
你擁有這間調查局的所有資源  不要害怕
Paper samples from  every regional manufacturer.
每個地區製造商的紙張樣品
Mr. Osborne, this is Mr. Tolson.  Supply Mr. Osborne whatever he needs...
奧斯本先生 這位是托爾森  協助奧斯本先生 不管他有什麼需要
...to conclude without a doubt that  these letters came from the same author.
以百分百斷定  這些信出自同一人之手
Hmm?
嗯？
Gentlemen, please. Thank you.
先生們 請離開 謝謝
- Should we tell the attorney general?  - So he can say no a third time?
- 我們是不是應該告訴檢察官？  - 好讓他第三次拒絕我們？
- Just post a sign, like this one.  - What would you like it to say, "keep out"?
- 掛個牌子 像這個一樣  - 你想說什麼，「禁止入內」？
"The Bureau of investigations  Technical Laboratory."
「調查局技術實驗室」
Have it carved and nailed to the wall.  If he wants it gone, he'll have to tear it out.
雕刻好 釘在牆上  如果有人想要撤了它 他還得花點力氣
It's time we at least have one thing  the bad guys don't.
是時候我們至少有  犯罪分子沒有的東西了
Decorating skills?
裝飾技巧？
Science, Clyde. Science.
是科學 克萊德
Uh, the ink is different,  but the handwriting is a match.
墨水不同  但筆跡吻合
Whoever Mr. Condon is corresponding with  is the person who wrote the original note.
不管是誰在和康登先生交涉  就是那個寫第一張字條的人
Or Condon wrote all the notes himself.
或者康登寫了所有的字條
Lindbergh is planning on using  Condon to deliver the ransom.
林德伯格正計劃讓康登  來送那些贖金
- May have already happened.  - Call the internal Revenue Service.
- 或許已經送去了  - 聯繫內部稅收部門
Get them to Lindbergh's home.  I insist that all those bills be marked.
讓他們去林德伯格家  我要讓所有的鈔票都做好標記
Yes, sir.
是
Ls that all, Mr. Hoover?  I have a 2:30 p.m. class to teach.
就這樣了嗎 胡佛先生？  我兩點半還有課
No, you don't.  Consider your pay doubled.
不 你不用去了  你的薪水將會翻倍
You work for your country now,  Mr. Osborne. Congratulations.
你現在為國家做事了 奧斯本先生  祝賀你
Doctor!
醫生！
Have you gotted the money?
拿到錢了嗎？
I can't bring the money till I see the baby.
沒見到孩子之前  我不能把錢帶來
I promise you there's no police.
我保證沒有警察
It's too dangerous.
太危險了
Stop! Stop this now!
停！快停！
No one's gonna harm you.
沒人會傷害你
If they catch me, they will.
如果他們抓住我那就會了
No, they only want the child.
不 他們只想要這個孩子
They'll give me 30 years if I'm caught.  They could burn me.
如果我被抓 會被判30年  這會毀了我
No. No.
不 不
I didn't do it.
不是我幹的
I'm only the messenger.
我只是個送信的
Eh!
What if the baby is dead?
如果孩子已經死了呢？
Would I burn if the baby is dead?
孩子死了的話我是不是就完了？
Why would we be meeting  if the baby was dead?
如果孩子已經死了  那我們還見面幹嘛？
Place another ad in the paper  when you have the money.
你拿到錢再登一個廣告
So if a ransom had to be paid,  we needed those bills traced.
如果贖金必須支付  我們需要追蹤這些鈔票
We brought in the lRS, and, for his  own good, we had to force his hand.
我們叫來了國稅局的人  出於他的考慮 我們必須強迫他如此
I thought gold notes were going  out of circulation, Mr. lrey.
我總覺得黃金證明這種東西  早就已經不流通了
That's our hope.
這才是我們的希望
It'll make these bills more identifiable.
這會讓這些鈔票更有辨識度
I have no need for the money.  I just want my son.
我不需要這些錢  我只想要我兒子回來
This isn't just about your son,  Mr. Lindbergh.
這不僅僅關乎您的兒子  林德伯格先生
If these kidnappers go free,  then no child in this country will be safe.
如果這些綁架犯逍遙法外  這個國家就沒有一個孩子是安全的了
That's why I've assembled a 26-man team,  headed by Special Agent Sisk here.
這就是為什麼我已經組成了一支26人的隊伍  由特別探員西斯科帶領
And if they find out you're involved,  I may never see my son again.
假如他們發現你有參與此事  我會永遠見不到我兒子了吧
Mr. Lindbergh, sir,  we will not pursue a single lead...
林德伯格先生  我們不會有任何超前的行為
...until your child is safe  in his mother's arms.
直到您的孩子平安回到母親的懷抱
You have my word, sir.
我向您保證
The kidnapping of  Charles A. Lindbergh, Jr., was a tragedy...
小查爾斯·A·林德伯格的綁架案  是一場悲劇...
...not only to Colonel and Mrs. Lindbergh,  but to the nation.
不僅對於科內爾和林德伯格夫人  還有整個國家
His abduction from his Hopewell home  was a challenge to America.
他從家中被綁架這件事  對整個美國都是挑戰
This ladder, the only clue  to the kidnapping, was homemade.
梯子 綁架案的唯一線索  是自己手工造的
Let the developments in the Lindbergh  case start a new drive...
讓林德伯格案件的一切進展  作為新的力量...
...to wipe out the stain,  not only of that wanton kidnapping...
消滅一切骯髒  不僅僅是這次放肆的綁架案
...but of all kidnapping and crimes.
包括所有的綁架和犯罪
Hey, doctor!
嘿 醫生！
Give your word not to open for six hours.
他告訴你六小時之內不要打開
Thank you.
謝謝
I talked him out of 20,000 dollars.
我跟他談下來2萬
I'd prefer him happy than save the money.  I don't want to upset him.
我選擇讓他高興點 而不是省錢  我不想讓他生氣
Where is the baby?
孩子在哪裡？
I promised not to open this for six hours.
我保證六小時之內不打開這個
You gave your word, I did not.
你說你的 我沒有說
"The boy is on boat Nelly.  It is a small boat, 28 feet long.
「孩子在奈麗號船上  是一艘小船 28尺長」
Two persons are on the boat.  They are innocent.
「有兩個人在船上 他們是無辜的」
You'll find the boat between Horseneck's  Beach and Gay Head near Elizabeth island."
「船在荷森內克海灘和  伊莉莎白島旁邊的蓋荷鎮之間」
That's Nantucket, right?
是在楠塔基特 是吧？
What was in the boat?
船裡面有什麼？
There was no boat.
根本就沒有船
Lindbergh didn't trust us.  He wanted to do things his way.
林德伯格沒有信任我們  他要按自己的方式來
And who can blame him?  No one respected us at that time.
誰能怪他呢  當時沒有人尊重我們調查局
Mr. Hoover, we've been calling.
胡佛先生  我們一直在找你
Edgar.
埃德加
Time to go, Agent Garrison. Right now.
該走了 加裡森調查員  現在
The Attorney General has authorized  your wiretaps.
總檢察長已經授權了  你的竊聽器
Very good, Miss Gandy.
很好 甘迪
Edgar, are you sure about this?  Once you do this, Edgar, it's done.
埃德加 你確定要這麼做嗎？  你要是這麼做了 事情就這麼定了
When I prove myself correct, we will have  saved this country another revolution.
我證明我是對的以後  我們可以再次避免國家陷入革命
History will remember that, Clyde.
歷史會記住我們的 克萊德
But if you are wrong...
但假如你錯了...
...history will remember it as an  illegal move over a petty grudge.
歷史也會記住這是一次  因為小的恩怨產生的非法行為
Do you consider our reputation petty,  Mr. Tolson?
你覺得我們的名聲是小事嗎  托爾森？
- No, I...  - Then order the wires.
- 不 我...  - 那就去訂這些電線
- Can we discuss this over dinner?  - After you've ordered the wires.
- 我們能不能晚飯時候討論一下？  - 在你訂了電線以後
Yes, sir.
是
The director's on his way.
局長已經在路上了
- Ahem.  - After you.
您請
Wait, please.
等等
- Harvey's Restaurant, sir?  - No, to the White House.
- 去哈維餐館？  - 不 去白宮
We were in the midst  of a Great Depression...
我們正在經歷大蕭條
...and breaths away from  history's worst war.
被史上最嚴重的戰爭  壓得喘不過氣
We needed more power to protect,  but, as with every new president...
我們需要更多的權力來保護  但 每次有新的總統上任
...this Bureau's future and my very job  was being drawn into question.
調查局的未來 以及我個人的職位  都要被打上問號
- The president is ready to see you now.  - Alrighty.
- 總統先生可以見你了  - 好的
Come in. Have a seat, Mr. Hoover.
進來吧 請坐 胡佛先生
It's the same dance each time.  They make me wait.
每次都是一樣的戲碼  他們讓我一直等
They imagine I'm sweating, that they're  gonna show me who's boss, I play along.
他們想像我會緊張流汗  然後他們就擺明自己才是老大 我是單打獨鬥
Thank you.
謝謝
And then did you show him  the transcript?
你給他看了那些記錄副本嗎？
No. He didn't want to read it.  That was unique.
不 他不想看  這很特殊
He wanted me to tell him about it.
他想讓我口頭告訴他
What, how you came across it?
那麼你是怎麼說的？
No, I explained to him up front  we never expected to find Mrs. Roosevelt...
我就直接跟他說  我們不曾想到會抓到羅斯福夫人...
...in the bedroom of  a known communist agitator...
會在一個知名的共產主義分子的臥室裡
...much less having what sounded like  an intimate moment.
聽起來像是很親密
That I needed his advice  on how to proceed.
我需要他指示該如何繼續調查
I wanted to let him know he had an ally.
我想讓他知道  他還是有盟友的
Before he had a chance  to ask you to resign.
在他要求你自己辭職之前
Exactly.
就是這樣
When I was finished,  he simply pushed the file aside...
我說完以後  他就把文件推到一邊
...as if he was unconcerned with it.
就像他根本不關心
Clyde, the President of the United States  is afraid.
克萊德 美國的總統害怕了
What, he's afraid of you?
他害怕你？
Of a potential invasion from abroad.
害怕潛在的來自國外的侵略
We'll have two glasses  of your finest champagne.
來兩杯你們最好的香檳
Of course, Mr. Hoover.
馬上 胡佛先生
- Ahem.  - You're drinking now?
你開始喝酒了？
We're celebrating, Clyde,  we're celebrating.
只是慶祝 克萊德
You know I feel I could trust you  with anything, right?
你知道 我覺得我可以  任何事都信任你 是嗎？
Well, I'd like to think so.
我很樂意這麼認為
The president signed a secret order...
總統簽署了一份密令
...granting me increased power  of surveillance...
給予我更多的監視權...
...secret surveillance of communists  and radicals, without warrant.
秘密監視共產主義分子和激進者的權利  不需要任何授權
Ls that legal?
這合法？
Sometimes you need  to bend the rules a little...
有時候 你需要過界一些...
...in order to keep  your country safe, right?
來保護國家的安全  是吧？
And to make sure I hadn't heard it wrong,  I clarified this with Secretary of State Hull.
為了保證我沒有聽錯  我還和國務卿赫爾證實了
And he said, and I quote, "You go ahead  and investigate those cocksuckers."
他說 我引用一下  「去吧 調查那些口交的傢伙們」
- Vulgar.  - Hmm, agreed.
- 好粗俗啊  - 同意
Clyde...
克萊德
...I've been meaning  to ask you something.
我一直想要問你一件事
Feel free.
問吧
I need someone who understands  what's at stake here...
我需要一個人  理解現在什麼是危在旦夕
...you understand?
你明白嗎？
Someone who I can trust...
一個我可以信任的人
...an associate director of the Bureau.
調查局的副局長
I know you've only been in your  current position for, what, 12 months now.
我知道 你在你現在的位置  只做了差不多12個月
Oh, almost 18 now, sir.
將近18個月了
You're missing my point, Clyde.
你沒理解我說的 克萊德
I want you to be my number-two man.
我需要你做我的二把手
I'm not much for the spotlight, Edgar.
我並不適應那些聚光燈 埃德加
I need you, Clyde.
我需要你 克萊德
Do you understand? I need you.
你明白嗎？  我需要你
On one condition.
只有一個條件
Good day or bad,  whether we agree or disagree...
不管這一天是好是壞  不管我們是否同意過...
...we never miss a lunch  or a dinner together.
我們永遠都要一起吃午飯和晚餐
Well, I would have it no other way.
我也不會同意其他的條件
Hey, pull over.
嘿 停車
- Only a half a mile to Mount Rose.  - Can't wait.
- 離玫瑰山只有半英里了  - 等不了了
Orville!
歐威爾！
In the end, the child's body  was found just within sight...
最終 孩子的屍體被發現...
...of Mr. Lindbergh's home.
就在林德伯格家視野範圍內
The body was blackened...
屍體已經變黑
...the left leg missing  from the knee down.
左腿膝蓋以下都不見了
There was a visible fracture on the skull.
頭骨上有明顯的骨折
He'd suffered a violent blow to the head.  I told them months ago.
他頭上受到了強大的外力擊打  我幾個月前就告訴他了
He must've fallen on the way down,  with the baby in his arms.
他在爬下去的時候肯定摔了  手裡抱著孩子
We are the sinners, Edgar.
我們都有罪 埃德加
We tolerated lawlessness in the land  until it grew to diabolical proportions.
是我們如此縱容無法無天的行為  讓它們變成窮凶極惡的犯罪
The baby's blood is on all our hands,  Edgar.
我們的手上沾滿了孩子的鮮血  埃德加
On your hands, Edgar.
你的手上
Yes, Mother.
是啊 母親
Six weeks after the kidnapping...
綁架案六周以後
...Congress passed the Lindbergh Law...
國會通過了林德伯格法案
...making kidnapping a federal offense.
把綁架定為國家級犯罪
The right to make arrests followed  and the right to bear arms.
有了拘捕的權利  以及攜帶槍支的權利
So I continued collecting the finest  scientific minds in the country.
所以我繼續聚集著  全國最好的科學頭腦
He claims to be the world expert  on wood analysis.
他說他是世界上最好的  木材鑒定專家
It's easy to be the expert if you're the  only person in the world with any interest.
假如你是世界上唯一有某種興趣的人  成為專家很容易
He does claim he can tell  as much from a cut of wood...
他聲稱從木頭的斷面  他可以鑒定出...
...as a doctor can from an autopsy.  - Ah.
- 和醫生屍檢獲得的信息一樣多  - 這樣
He has, um, social difficulties.
他有 呃 社交困難
He is mentally ill, isn't he?
他精神有問題 是吧？
He's only as mad as you are. Sir.
只不過跟你一樣瘋狂罷了
This was supposed to be temporary,  Mr. Hoover.
這本應該只是暫時的  胡佛先生
If you want your Sherlock Holmes  playing time...
假如你想要繼續你這福爾摩斯的遊戲...
Where do you suggest we go, sir, where?
那你覺得我們還能去哪？
I suggest you take your case  to Congress.
我建議你去國會解決這個問題
Fine, sir. Have it your way.
很好 那就照你說的
I'll tell people we could not solve the case  because we could not afford laboratories...
我們就告訴人們 只是因為無法負擔實驗室  我們就不能解決這些案件
...and the Attorney General  wouldn't allow us to use his lounge.
而總檢察長不願意我們佔用他的休息室
Fine. Now get your science fair project  out of here.
行吧 把你的這些科學實驗搬出去
Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
是 馬上
Gentlemen, keep working.
繼續工作
Mr. Tolson,  let's get the president on the phone.
托爾森  幫我接到總統的電話
The depravations of vicious outlaws, roving  from state to state like packs of wolves...
惡性犯罪的日益嚴重  像一群狼一樣從一個州遊蕩到另一個州
...amounts to an actual  armed invasion of America.
成為真正武裝侵蝕美國的力量
We must outsmart and outwit the criminal,  foreign and domestic.
我們必須智取這些犯罪分子  不論是國外還是國內的
They have chemists building bombs.  We need chemists tracing their efforts.
他們有化學藥品來製造炸彈  我們就也需要化學藥品來追蹤他們
We must have the most advanced  force in the world...
我們必須有世界上最先進的力量
...if we are to have the safest nation  on earth.
假如我們想要成為世界上最安全的國家
And, please, gentlemen, let us not  for a moment lose sight of our goals:
先生們 請不要 哪怕就一刻  失去我們的視野和目標
To protect the honest citizen...
保護忠誠的國民
...to teach the criminal that  regardless of his subterfuges...
告訴犯罪分子  不管他有什麼托詞
...his twisting, his squirming  and slimy wriggling...
不管他如何扭曲  如何在泥濘中蠕動
...he cannot escape the one  inexorable rule of law enforcement...
...that you can't get away with it.
沒人可以避免
Thank you.
謝謝
Thank you, Mr. Hoover.
謝謝 胡佛先生
But your agency is already one of the most  well-funded in Washington, is it not?
但是你的機構已經是華盛頓  財政支持最多的機構之一了 是嗎？
Yes, that is true, sir...
是的 的確...
...but our car and bank robbery recoveries  totaled 6.5 million last year...
但是我們去年的劫車 劫銀行的案件  恢復到了650萬美元的高度
...and our budget is only,  well, two million.
我們的預算只有200萬
Unlike other departments in Washington,  we actually run a profit.
不像華盛頓的其他部門  我們看上去還掙了點嘛
We cannot quantify  the value of our successes...
我們不能用數字來  衡量我們的成功...
...with the hoodlums Pretty Boy Floyd,  Baby Face Nelson, Machine Gun Kelly...
包括「帥哥弗洛伊德」（銀行搶劫者）  「娃娃臉尼爾森」（銀行搶劫者）「機關鎗凱利」（黑幫）這些惡棍
...and other hoodlums of that nature.
還有其他很多的惡人
Mr. Hoover, is it true that you spend  the Bureau's money on advertising?
胡佛先生 你把調查局的經費  花在了廣告方面 這是真的嗎？
We are not permitted to engage  in advertising of any kind, sir. No.
我們不允許任何形式的廣告
But you take part, for instance, in the  making of radio shows and comic books.
但你參與了 比如說  廣播節目的製作 還有漫畫書
I've listened to several  of these G-Men programs.
我聽過幾次政府官員的電台節目
Your picture seems to be shown  in conjunction with them quite frequently.
你的照片似乎經常跟他們出現在一起
We declined emphatically to lend  any form of endorsement...
我們強調過  拒絕給他們任何支持...
...had nothing to do with their production,  furnished no advice, technical or otherwise.
那些和他們的產品無關的東西  不提供建議 技術 或是任何東西
Well, the very advertisement says  that broadcasts were...
這條廣告說  廣播是...
..."true reflections,  as contained in the official records...
「最真實的反映官方記錄中...」
...based on actual cases from the files  of the Federal Bureau of investigation...
「根據聯邦調查局的真實案件改編」
...Saturday night at 8:00."
「週六晚上8點檔」
Mr. Hoover,  what are your exact qualifications...
胡佛先生  你到底有何資質...
...for your position of leadership  in this Bureau?
處於你現在所在調查局的領導地位？
My qualifications, sir?
我的資質？
Nineteen years with the  Department of Justice. Nineteen.
在司法部工作了19年  19年
Twelve as director.
其中12年是調查局局長
In all that time,  you ever make an arrest yourself?
那段時間  你有沒有親自逮捕犯罪分子？
I have made investigations.  I administer several cases at once.
我做了調查  我同時主管好幾件案子
Well, that's not what I asked.
這沒有回答我的問題
The comic books show you with a machine  gun, making arrests. Ls that just fiction?
漫畫書裡有你拿著機關鎗  逮捕犯罪分子的情景 這只是編造？
I am responsible for  thousands of arrests, sir.
我負責了幾千次的逮捕
So you admit it is pure fiction.
所以你承認那些都是編的
In fact, it wasn't you who hunted down  and captured John Dillinger at all.
實際上 不是你把約翰·迪林傑  打倒並抓獲的
It was Agent Purvis. Ls that correct?
是博維斯探員  是嗎？
I was in charge of all of those  investigations...
我負責了所有的這些調查...
...but, no, sir, I have not personally  made an arrest.
但的確 我個人並未做出任何拘捕
Any other questions, gentlemen?
還有別的問題嗎？
Let's bring it to a vote.
我們投票決定吧
Put those away.
把這些拿走
Well, that didn't go well.
事情不太順利啊
We spend our lives working  and we get a political attack?
我們拚命工作  結果落得被政治攻擊？
What does he expect, crimes to go  unsolved? Why is he fighting me?
他想要怎樣 案件沒法解決？  他幹嘛跟我作對？
I want you to start a file  on Senator McKellar.
你去開始調查麥克凱勒參議員
I want four agents on him at all times.
安排四個探員同時調查
I want to know what's in his trash,  photograph him at dinner.
我要知道他丟的垃圾裡都有什麼  我要他每天吃晚飯的照片
Don't get in the car. You can walk back.
不要上這輛車 你可以走回去
We have lunch.  We don't miss lunch, no matter what.
埃德加 我們要吃午飯的  我們不論如何都是一起吃午飯的 記得嗎？
You pulled away from me in there.
在裡面的時候  你就那樣離開丟下我一人
You perjured yourself, Edgar,  and the lie was an easily provable one.
你給自己作偽證了 埃德加  還是個很容易被識破的謊言
There's no telling  how much worse it could've been.
如果你還要繼續這些  我都不敢說事情會變得多糟糕
Find Agent Purvis. He is to be  demoted immediately or, better yet, fired.
把博維斯探員找出來  馬上把他降職 或者最好是炒了
Firing the man who killed John Dillinger  would be a PR disaster.
把抓到約翰·迪林傑的人炒了  這會是重大人力損失
Then he is to spend the rest of his career  behind a desk.
那他就餘生都在辦公桌前度過吧
And if he'd like to keep that job,  he'd best stay out of the papers. Go.
如果他想保住飯碗  他最好離重要文件遠點 開車
I don't know who I can trust anymore.
我不知道我還能信任誰
Only you.
只有您了
Only you, Mother.
只有您了 母親
You're all I have to keep me safe,  you understand that?
你是我唯一擁有的 保佑我安全的人  你知道嗎？
Please, Mother,  let me take you to a doctor.
求你了 媽媽  讓我帶你去看醫生
A simple examination isn't unholy, is it?
簡單地檢查一下沒什麼不好的
Mother.
媽
Mother, please.
媽 拜託了
Faith, Edgar.
信念 埃德加
Faith.
信念
Don't wilt like a little flower.
不要像一朵小花一樣枯萎
Be strong.
要堅強
Yes, Mother.
是的 母親
I will.
我會的
if what Congress valued more  than wits and brains was muscle...
假如國會更喜歡力量  而不是頭腦和智慧
...if what they hungered for  was an armed American hero...
如果他們更需要的是  一個武裝起來的美國英雄
...then I was willing to risk my very life  and give them both.
那我會冒著生命危險  做到兩者兼備
Move.
行動
Go.
走
Hold it, government agents!
站住！政府探員！
The arrest is mine to make!
這次逮捕應該是我來！
Move.
閃開
Mr. Karpis, you are under arrest.
卡佩斯先生 你被逮捕了
Mr. Hoover himself.  I'm gonna be famous.
胡佛親自出馬啊  我要出名了
Put the handcuffs on him.
把他銬起來
Don't move, Mr. Mahan.
不許動 麥漢先生
Blow it down.
放倒它
Move.
行動
Mr. Brunette, you are under arrest.
本內特先生 你被逮捕了
Alvin Karpis said he couldn't be taken alive,  but we took him without firing a shot.
埃爾文·卡佩斯說他不能被活捉  但我們一槍都沒開就抓住了他
And let me tell you, he shook all over.  His voice, his hands, and his knees.
這麼跟你說吧 他抖得跟篩子似的  聲音 手 還有膝蓋
You arrested Harry Campbell in Toledo  and Brunette in Manhattan?
你還在托雷多逮捕了哈利·坎貝爾  在曼哈頓逮捕了本內特？
And William Mahan in California.
還有在加州逮捕了威廉·麥漢
But let me clarify  without a shadow of a doubt...
不過我要再次申明  這絕對地...
...this was a "we" job, not an "I" job.
是團隊合作的結果  而不是我個人的成就
Edgar, look at this.  We made the Post Toasties box.
埃德加 看看這個  我們做了這個麥片盒子
"Melvin Purvis,  the FBl agent that caught Dillinger."
「梅爾文·博維斯  抓住迪林傑的調查局探員」
Write the cereal-maker.  Let them know...
聯繫麥片製造商  讓他們知道...
Oh. "Junior G-Man." Hmm.
噢 政府官員的電台節目
Tell them they ought to print any further  boxes to read "former agent of the FBl."
告訴他們必須把以後所有的盒子印成  「前調查局探員」
Sit down, Clyde.  I'm gonna read something.
坐下 克萊德  我給你念段東西
"Only eight more days.
「還有8天」
Funny how even the dearest face  will fade away in time.
「雖然可笑 但最親愛的人的臉  就要消失了」
Most clearly, I remember your eyes...
「最清楚地記住了你的眼睛...」
...with a sort of teasing smile in them,  and the feeling of that soft spot...
「眼神裡有挑逗的笑意  還有那最柔軟的一點...」
...just northeast of the corner  of your mouth against my lips."
「就在你嘴唇的東北角  正對我的雙唇」
What is it?
這是什麼？
It's a letter from Lorena Hickok...
是一封來自羅蕾娜·西科克的信
...the White House reporter with  the bad breath, to Mrs. Roosevelt.
就是那個有口臭的白宮報道員  寫給羅斯福太太的
No. What are you gonna do with it?
不會吧  那你要拿這個怎麼辦？
Nothing. I accused her  of having an affair with a man...
不怎麼樣  我指控過她和男人有外遇...
...and Old Horse Face is having  an affair with Mrs. Bat Breath!
現在這位馬臉老阿姨  要和口臭小姐有一腿了！
- A woman! Can you believe it?  - Mm.
一個女人！你相信嗎？
Oh, excuse me, Mr. Hoover.  They'd like to see you in the laboratory.
噢 打擾了 胡佛先生  他們要你去實驗室一趟
Yes, Miss Gandy. You tell them  I'll be there in one minute. Thank you.
好的 甘迪 告訴他們  我馬上就下去 謝謝
We'll get to this later.
我們等會兒再處理這個
Speaking of horses, Clyde,  I'm going to Del Mar this weekend.
說到馬 克萊德  我這個週末會去德爾馬爾（加州）一趟
I was thinking of taking  a quick vacation...
我在考慮度一個簡短的假期
...and, well,  I thought you'd like to join me.
我想你會不會樂意跟我一起去
Well, I've never been  to the horse races, Edgar.
我還從沒看過賽馬比賽呢  埃德加
Well, it's wonderful.
很有意思的
And between me and you, when I lose,  the track, they actually cover the losses.
就對你說啊 如果我賭輸了  他們會幫我付這錢
- So, what happens if you win?  - They still pay.
- 那如果你贏了呢？  - 那還是他們付錢
Then where's the thrill?
那這有什麼刺激的？
In the sun that falls on the stands,  the hotel rooms, the service...
陽光灑在看台上  酒店房間 好的服務...
...the restaurants, but, most of all,  Clyde, it's the company.
還有餐廳 但最重要的是  克萊德 是和你同去的人
- Come with me.  - I'd love to.
- 和我一起去吧  - 我很樂意
Fantastic. I'll have Miss Gandy  make all the arrangements.
太好了 我會讓甘迪  安排好一切
Well, I can't go now. But maybe  in a couple months after I've saved up.
其實我不能現在去  但或許過兩個月 等我存點錢
- It's completely covered, Clyde.  - Edgar, I can't let you do that.
- 費用都我包了 克萊德  - 埃德加 這可不行
Listen, you've done so much for me,  for this Bureau. Consider it a thank you.
聽著 你為我做了這麼多事  也為了調查局 就當是我謝謝你
I don't know that I'd feel comfortable.
我不知道我會不會覺得舒服啊
I'll get a suite with adjoining rooms...
這樣告訴你吧  我會定一個套間 有相鄰的臥室
...rather than having us stay separate.  That'll be savings enough.
而不是兩個人分開訂房間  這樣就節省多了
Deal.
成交
What do you have for me, Mr. Koehler?
有什麼新發現嗎 科勒先生？
Well, as you can see, ahem,  there are several kinds of wood here.
你能看到  這裡有幾種木頭
Pine, birch, fir, and, if you look closely,  you will see...
松木 樺木 冷杉 還有  如果你仔細看還能看到...
- Thank you.  - Mr. Tolson.
- 謝謝  - 托爾森先生
That each has its own internal markings,  rings and knots...
每種木材都有自己獨特的內部紋理  年輪和梔...
...and its own external markings from  the machinery used to mill the raw timber...
還有獨特的外在紋理  是機器打磨原木的時候形成的
...and these that mark the tools  used to build the ladder.
這些說明了製造梯子的工具
The question is, how does this help us  identify the kidnappers, Mr. Koehler?
問題是 這些能如何幫我們找到  綁架犯呢 科勒先生？
I need more money, sir.
我需要更多經費
- More money, sir, for what?  - Postage.
- 更多經費？為了幹嘛？  - 郵資
I need to write every mill  on the East Coast...
我需要給東岸的每家廠子寫信
...and see if their blades  match these marks.
看他們的刀片切口是否和這個吻合
Hmm.
嗯
I want a report from each mill  and a map tracking all leads.
把每個廠家的信息寫進報告  並把追蹤的所有線索畫成地圖
By the time I get back from New York,  I want something to report.
我回到紐約以後  我要你有點料可以報告
Good day.
日安
Just like the communist radicals  before them...
就像他們之前的共產主義激進分子一樣
...the gangster fell from favor.
黑幫也沒落了
Now, finally, children dreamed  of joining the FBl.
現在終於 孩子們夢想  成為聯邦調查局探員
On your feet. On your feet.
站起來 站起來
Yeah?
喂？
He's taking his shower. Any message?
他在洗澡 可以留個言嗎？
There ain't any shower there, copper.
那裡根本不能洗澡
Miss Temple!
鄧波兒小姐！
Mr. Hoover, I was wondering  if you would join my police force.
胡佛先生 我在想  你願不願意加入我的警力組
Why, yes, Miss Temple.
當然了 鄧波兒小姐
If you agree to be an honorary G-Woman,  and give me one little kiss.
假如你願意變成一名體面的女特工  再親一親我
I don't know if your wife would approve,  Mr. Hoover.
我不知道你的妻子會不會允許了
But, you see,  I still live with my mother.
但你看  我還和我媽媽住在一起
Oh. Okay.
噢 好吧
- Look this way!  - That's real spiffy.
- 看這邊！  - 真漂亮
Nice smile. Thank you very much.
微笑一個 謝謝
Excuse me, sir. Can we get a statement?
先生 我們需要一個說明...
How'd you like the picture?
您喜歡這部電影嗎？
This way, Mr. Hoover!
這邊請
After you, Mother.
您先請 母親
Should we go to the club?
我們去俱樂部嗎？
After we drop Mother off at the hotel.
等我們把媽媽送回賓館
I have you at a table with Anita Colby.
你們和阿妮塔·科爾比（演員）一桌
Lela Rogers and her daughter Ginger  have asked if they can join.
樂拉·羅傑斯和她的女兒金吉爾（演員）  也問了她們能不能一起
As long as it's near the front.
多多益善
Miss Rogers, pleasure to meet you.  This must be your mother.
羅傑斯小姐 很高興見到你  這應該就是你的母親了
Hello.
你好
J. Edgar Hoover. This is Clyde Tolson.  Anita, good to see you.
我是J·埃德加·胡佛 這位是克萊德·托爾森  阿妮塔 很高興見到你
The bullet entered  the back of the head...
子彈是從後腦勺射入...
...and exited through the front  near his cheek.
從前面大概臉頰的地方穿出
The thing that most people don't  realize is that there is little blood.
大多數人沒有認識到的是  其實流血很少
The heat from the bullet actually  seals the wound as it enters...
子彈產生的熱量  會把入射產生的傷口密封起來
...so the crime scene is far more peaceful  than is depicted in your moving pictures.
所以其實犯罪現場比你們電影中  描繪的要正常多了
And little Lindy.  Did you see the child with your own eyes?
還有小林迪  您親眼看到這個孩子了嗎？
Those are details I wouldn't disclose...
有一些案件的細節...
...with a refined group of women  such as yourselves.
最好還是不要透露給  你們這些如此優雅的女人
I couldn't bear to make you shed a tear.  But I assure you this, we are on the case.
我可不能讓你們傷心流淚  但我向你們保證 我們仍舊在查案
I saw the Lindberghs in Paris.  I hardly recognized them.
我在巴黎見到了林德伯格一家  都差點認不出了
Hmm.
嗯
Only justice can bring reason  back to their lives.
只有正義才能讓他們  重新找回生活的意義
But I might share one confidential  clue with you, if you swear to secrecy.
我可以跟你們說說已經找到的機密線索  你們要發誓保密
Of course.
當然
The gold notes from  the ransom money have surfaced.
贖金中金色標記的鈔票已經浮出水面
And can you guess where?
猜猜是在哪裡？
Tell us. Please, Mr. Hoover.
拜託 告訴我們吧
In the Bronx, on three occasions.
在布朗克斯（紐約）  出現了三次
And each one of the shop owners claim...
每個店主都說...
...they received them from a man with  a pointed chin and a German accent.
鈔票都來自一個  有尖下巴和德國口音的男人
Take my word for it, Mr. Hoover.
聽我說 胡佛先生
All the admiration in the world  can't fill the spot love goes.
就算全世界都仰慕  沒有愛 還是會少了一塊
Hmm.
嗯
Or keep your bed warm.
或者說 可以溫暖你的床
I serve my country, Miss Colby.
我是國家的人 科爾比小姐
The nation's admiration  is more than enough for me. Heh.
國家對我的讚許  已經是無上的榮譽
But it likely makes for a cold bed.
但不管如何 你的床鋪還是冰冷
Mr. Hoover, would it be out of the question  to bother you for a dance?
胡佛先生  您是否考慮和我跳一支舞？
Oh, uh, how do you mean?
這是什麼意思？
Well, simply a dance.
只是跳支舞
You do dance, don't you?
你會跳舞的吧？
Well, that is a skill  that, um, I haven't yet mastered.
呃 這倒是我還未掌握的技能
And the night is getting long,  isn't it, Mr. Tolson? Mr. Tolson?
已經不早了 是嗎  托爾森？
No time like the present.  It's my favorite song, come on.
沒有比現在更好的了  這是我最愛的歌 來吧
It's time we leave.  Uh, we have a great deal of work.
我們該走了  我們還有很多工作要做
We... We...  We have a great deal of work tomorrow...
我們...我們...  我們明天還有很多工作
...and I'm afraid we don't have time  to dance. We're very busy, aren't we?
恐怕沒有時間跳舞了  我們很忙的
Yes.
是的
And my sincere apologies. I...
我真誠地道歉
Right now, Mr. Tolson.  Thank you very much.
托爾森 我們現在走吧  非常感謝你們
- Good evening.  - Ha, ha.
晚安
Good night.
I don't...
我不...
I...
我...
I don't... I don't like to...  I don't like to dance, Mother.
我不喜歡跳舞 母親
- I don't like to da...  - Edgar, go look in the mirror.
- 我不喜歡跳...  - 埃德加 去照照鏡子
Talk the way the doctor taught you to.  Be my little Speedy.
按照醫生教的方法說話  小飛毛腿
I can spit my words out with... With...
我可以說...說...
I can spit my words out with precision,  diction, and clarity.
我可以準確地 清晰地 用詞準確地說話
I can sp... Spit my words out with precision,  diction, and clarity.
我可以準確地...  清晰地 用詞準確地說話
I'm a proficient, remarkable lad,  capable of remarkable feats.
我工作嫻熟 出眾  做了了不起的事
I'm a profic... Mother.  Mother, I don't like to dance.
我...  媽 我不喜歡跳舞
Mostly I don't like to dance with women.
應該說我不喜歡和女人跳舞
I think it's time you knew this.
我覺得是時候讓你知道這個了
And I find it humiliating  and I refuse to be humiliated.
我覺得這很丟人  我不喜歡丟人
Edgar, stop.
埃德加 別說了
Do you remember Barton Pincus?
你還記得巴頓·品克斯嗎？
Yes, Mother.
記得
His father was a watchmaker.
他的父親是鐘錶匠
He was 10 years younger than me  and you used to call him...
他比我小10歲  你叫他...
...Birdy or Daffy  or something to that effect.
博迪還是達菲  之類的吧
And do you remember  what happened to Daffy?
那你還記得達菲最後怎樣了嗎？
After the school custodian discovered him  in a hoop skirt and flower bonnet?
在學校發現他  穿了裙子 戴著有花的帽子以後？
He was made to stand outside  in front of the school...
他被迫站在學校外面...
...wearing the bonnet and skirt  as punishment.
穿著裙子 戴著花帽子  作為懲罰
Did you ever wonder why  we called him Daffy?
你就沒想過  我們為什麼叫他達菲？
For his odd behavior, I believe.
因為他奇怪的行為吧 我猜
It's short for "daffodil," Edgar.
那是「水仙花」的略稱
Do you remember what happened  to Daffodil Pincus?
你還記得這個娘炮最後怎樣了嗎？
Yes, Mother. He...
是的 他...
He shot himself six weeks after.
六周之後 他開槍自盡
That's right.
就是這樣
And I thank God every day that my own  sons don't suffer from his condition.
我每天都感謝上帝  我的兒子們不用遭受如此折磨
Edgar.
埃德加
I'd rather have a dead son  than a daffodil for a son.
我寧願要個死人  也不願要個娘炮的兒子
And now, I'm gonna teach you to dance.
現在 我來教你怎麼跳舞
Yes, Mother.
是
- Bring this right over here, please.  - Sure, sir.
- 把它拿到這裡來  - 是
All right. Now, when did you get  this shipment?
好 你是什麼時候接到這單的？
It's a long while back.  I'm thinking, uh, November 1931.
有陣子了  我想應該是1931年11月
Three months before the kidnapping.
綁架案的3個月前
All right. Thank you.
好的 謝謝
The lumberyard is a cash business,  there aren't any receipts or names.
伐木場是現金交易的  沒有留下任何收據或者名字
It tells us where he was shopping  before we were looking.
至少告訴我們  在犯案之前他都在哪裡買東西
Show me the addresses of where  the ransom bills have shown up.
給我指一指  那些贖金鈔票都出現在什麼地方
It's 456 West Third.
456號西三街
And 476 West Third.
還有476號西三街
And down the street right here.
還有下面這條街這裡
We knew who we were looking for.
我們知道要找的人是誰了
Someone who'd done business  in this neighborhood for years.
他是在這一片生活工作了很長時間的人
Someone who was still there.
應該還在那裡
He was average height, blue eyes.
他身高普通  有藍眼睛
High cheekbones and a pointy chin.
高顴骨 尖下巴
Yes, sir, a pointed chin  and an accent, like a...
是的 尖下巴  還有口音 像是...
German accent, maybe?
德國口音 大概？
A German with big cheekbones.
一個有高顴骨的德國人
Am I, uh, going to get him  in some kind of trouble?
我...會給他惹麻煩嗎？
Not if he didn't do anything wrong.  We're the FBl, son. We're the good guys.
他沒幹壞事就不會  我們是聯邦調查局的 我們是好人
It was deposited by Walter Lyle.
這是沃爾特·萊爾存的錢
He manages the gas station  up on Lexington and 127th.
他在列剋星敦大道和127街路口  開了個加油站
Walter Lyle?
你是沃爾特·萊爾？
You remember the man  that paid with this?
你還記得用這個付錢的男人嗎？
Yes, I remember him.  He bought 89 cents worth of gas.
我記得  他買了89分錢的汽油
And he paid with this bill?
他用這個付錢的？
Yes, sir. But I don't know him.  I haven't seen him since.
是的 但我不認識他  那之後就沒有見過
You would remember him  if he came in again?
如果他再來  你能認出來嗎？
Yeah, he was German, I think,  I mean, with an accent and pointed chin.
能啊 他是德國人吧 我想  我是說 有那種口音 還有尖下巴
- High cheekbones, right?  - Yeah. I looked at the bill funny.
- 還有高顴骨 是嗎？  - 是啊 我覺得這鈔票挺好笑的
He assured me he had  a hundred more like it at home.
他跟我拍胸脯說  他家裡還有這一樣的一百多張
You had a conversation with him?
你跟他聊了什麼？
No, that was it.
沒有 就這些了
Thank you, Mr. Lyle.
謝謝 萊爾先生
I wrote down the license plate number.
我有記下車牌號
That's the writing  along the edge of the bill.
就是寫在鈔票邊上的那個號碼
Let's go.
我們走
Miss Gandy, get Mr. Tolson.
甘迪 叫上托爾森
Agent Sisk.
西斯科探員
The New York Motor Vehicles Bureau  describes it as a blue 1930 Dodge sedan.
紐約機動車辦公室  說這是一輛1930年的藍色道奇轎車
The owner is a carpenter  born in Germany...
車主是一個德國出生的木匠
...lives at 1279 East 222nd Street  in the Bronx.
住在布朗克斯的東222街1279號
His name is Bruno Richard Hauptmann.
名字叫布魯諾·理查德·哈普特曼
Let's move.
行動
On September 19th, 1934...
1934年9月19日...
...before we could arrest  the most wanted man in America...
就在我們抓到這個  美國頭號通緝犯之前
...he'd been pulled over by a local cop  for a broken tail light.
他被當地警察要求停車  因為車尾燈壞了
Can't believe this.
真不敢相信
Pull over.
停車
FBl, put your hands up!
聯邦調查局！  舉起手來！
- Put them up!  - Ls there a problem?
- 舉起手來！  - 有問題嗎？
Get out of the car!
下車！
Bruno Hauptmann...
布魯諾·哈普特曼
...you are under arrest for the kidnapping  and murder of Charles Lindbergh, Jr.
你因涉嫌綁架及謀殺小查爾斯·林德伯格  而被逮捕
Cuff him, boys.
把他銬起來
We finally had him.
我們終於抓到了他
Now we had to convict,  but unlike trials of the past...
我們需要將他定罪  但不像以前的那些審判
...we now had forensics,  expert witnesses, and facts.
我們有法醫 專家證人  還有證據
We need a title, Agent Garrison.
我們需要起個標題  加裡森調查員
Right away, Mr. Hoover.
馬上就好
We are working, Miss Gandy.
我們正忙呢 甘迪
The tape came in.
磁帶送來了
Bring it to my private office.
拿到我的私密辦公室去
That'll be all for now, Agent Garrison.
這些就可以了  加裡森調查員
I just have to say...
我只是想說...
...you looked so beautiful  sitting across that bar.
你坐在那個酒吧對面的時候太美了
I saw you watching me.
我看到你在盯著我
I have to admit I was watching you...
我得承認...
...for a long time.
我看你好長時間了
Slow down a little bit.
慢一點
All right.
好
Let me take this off.
我來把這脫了
Turn around.
轉過去
You got it?
行嗎？
Miss Gandy, I told you  I am not to be disturbed.
甘迪 我跟你說了不能打擾
I'm sorry. Mr. Hoover?
對不起 胡佛先生
Yes, it's urgent. I have Agent Shanklin  on the line from Dallas.
是緊急事件  珊科林探員從達拉斯來電
My apologies, Mr. Hoover.
對不起 胡佛先生
I told Miss Gandy to put me through.
是我讓甘迪小姐讓我通話
What is it, Agent Shanklin?
什麼事 探員？
Sir, the president has been shot.
總統被槍殺了
Who else knows about this?
還有誰知道這件事？
No one, sir. I thought you should know  before the press reports it.
還沒有人  我想你應該在媒體之前知道
- Thank you, Agent Shanklin.  - Yes, sir.
- 謝謝  - 不用
Oh, that feels so good.
噢 感覺真棒
Get me Robert Kennedy immediately.
馬上把我接到羅伯特·肯尼迪
Mr. Hoover?
胡佛先生？
Mr. Kennedy,  the president has been shot.
肯尼迪先生  總統剛剛被槍殺了
What?
什麼？
Mr. Hoover? What?
胡佛先生？什麼？
Mr. Hoover?
胡佛先生？
It's Frosty Mountain in front...
現在領先的是「冷山」...
...by a length and a half.
領先一個半身位
That's Jazz third by six.
「爵士」在第三位 落後六個身位
Slapjack's fourth, final head.  Popstar Merell three quarters.
「巴掌傑克」第四位  「大明星梅瑞爾」落後四分之三個身位
Turning for home, Frosty Mountain under  the left by a fraction and a length and a half.
開始衝刺 「冷山」在左邊  領先一個半身位
Number five. He's gaining on them.
五號 要追上了
It's Frosty Mountain, now.
現在還是「冷山」領先
I'm not sure if I bet on that one.
我不確定我是不是押了他
Ah. We lost again, Clyde.
啊 我們又輸了 克萊德
Dextro back by a half-length on the rail.
「德克斯托」落後半個身位
Dextro now making his move.  Findlay gives him the whip.
「德克斯托」開始啟動了  芬德利抽打了他
Oh, there he goes, there he goes!
來了 來了
Come on, Dextro, come on, Dextro!
加油 德克斯托 加油！
- Did you see his shoes?  - Ha, ha.
你看到他的鞋子了嗎？
Desi Arnaz?
德斯·阿納茲？（音樂家 演員）
You mean the crocodile ones  with the horrible buckles across the top?
你是說那雙上面有很醜帶扣的  鱷魚皮鞋？
No, I didn't notice them one bit.
我一點都沒注意到
You'd think with their money  they'd have a bit of fashion sense...
你不覺得他們有那麼多錢  就不該對時尚敏感點嗎
Ha, ha.  - ...or at least pay someone to have it.
或者至少雇個對時尚敏感的人
Oh, and his faux-ginger wife.
噢 還有他那個人造一樣的老婆
When she walked in, I thought a hunter  was gonna pull a rifle on that hat of hers.
她走進來的時候 我都覺得會有獵人  一槍把她的帽子給轟了
It was like this, you see, like...
就像這樣 你看 就像...
Ha-ha-ha. That's right, with the feathers.
哈哈 是啊 那些羽毛
You know, I care so very much  for you, Clyde. I do.
你知道嗎 我真的很在乎你  克萊德 真的
And I love you, Edgar.
我也愛你 埃德加
ls everything okay?
你還好嗎？
Yes, yes, I'm fine.
我沒事
I'm fine.
I've been meaning  to ask you something, Clyde.
我一直想問你一件事 克萊德
Anything.
問吧
What do you think of Dorothy Lamour,  the actress?
你覺得那個女演員  桃樂絲·拉莫爾怎樣？
With Rudy Vallee at the Stork Club?
和魯迪·瓦力在斯托克俱樂部的那個？
Yes. That's the one.
是的 就是她
She's a little camp for me, but, heh...
對我來說是太女性化了吧 但是...
Well, I've been thinking of taking her up  on a proposal is all.
我是在想 要她跟我一起
For dinner?
吃晚餐？
No, no, not dinner.
不 不 不是晚餐
We've been to dinner several times now.
我們已經一起吃過晚餐好幾次了
When?
什麼時候？
Oh, in New York, when I've gone up  on the weekends.
噢 在紐約  我週末去那裡的時候
I see.
我知道了
I suppose what I'm... What I'm trying  to say here, Clyde, is, well...
我想...我想要說的是...  克萊德...是...
...l think it may be time for a Mrs. Hoover.
我覺得是時候有個胡佛夫人了
What, you don't like her? Ls that it?
你不喜歡她嗎？  是不是？
Don't you make a fool of me, Edgar.
你別讓我這麼難堪 埃德加
I'm not, Clyde,  I'm not making a fool of you.
我沒有  我沒有想讓你難堪
Have you...? Have you become physical?
你們...你們有做過了嗎？
Yes, we have.
有
What is it, Clyde?
怎麼了 克萊德？
Do you want me to be half a person?  Remain incomplete, is that what you want?
你想讓我一直過不了完整的生活？  這是你想要的嗎？
ls that what I am to you, incompletion?
我對你來說 只算是半吊子？
Clyde, pick that glass up immediately!
克萊德 給我馬上把這杯子撿起來！
No, I will not! I have no reason to!
不我不會！我沒理由這樣做！
I refuse! So, go on, fire me.
我拒絕！來啊 炒了我
Do it. Now!
快啊 現在就炒了我！
Get a hold of yourself.  You're acting like a fool!
你冷靜一下  這行為太愚蠢了
- Agh!  - Stop this!
住手！
Clyde! You have no shoes on,  for God's sakes!
克萊德！你沒穿鞋子 天哪！
No. No, I will not!  I won't even listen to you!
不 我不會  我不要聽你說了！
You will never tell me what to do!  You just lost that right!
你永遠不能對我發號施令了！  你沒有這個權利！
- Stop it!  - I see right through you!
- 住口！  - 我看透你了！
You're a scared, heartless,  horrible little man!
你就是個膽小的 沒良心的  差勁的小人！
- Unh! Don't you dare!  - Unh!
你竟敢...
Don't you ever do that again.
你以後膽敢再這樣做
I won't.
我不會了
Cly...
克萊...
Clyde, where are you going?
克萊德 你去哪？
Clyde, please. Clyde, don't leave me!
克萊德 求你了  不要留下我！
Clyde, please.
克萊德 求你了
Clyde, I'm sorry!
克萊德 對不起！
Clyde, please don't leave me!
克萊德 不要離開我！
Clyde, I'm begging you!
克萊德 求求你了！
I'm begging you, Clyde! Clyde, please.
我求你了 克萊德！  克萊德 拜託了
After all...
不管怎樣...
After all, we have another day of races.
不管怎樣 我們還有一天的賽馬要看
If you ever mention a lady friend again...
你以後要是再提起任何女性朋友...
...it will be the last time  that you share my company.
那我就再也不會出現在你身邊
Love you, Clyde.
我愛你 克萊德
Love you.
我愛你
Mr. Meter looks promising.
米特爾看上去挺有希望
- Unh. Ugh.  - What is it, Clyde?
怎麼了 克萊德？
Clyde?
克萊德？
Someone get a doctor.
快去叫醫生
Clyde.
克萊德
Someone get a doctor now!  Someone get a doctor!
快去叫醫生！  快去叫醫生！
Clyde, look at me. Look at me.
克萊德 看著我 看著我
Someone get a doctor now!
快點去叫醫生啊！
Help!
急救！
He'll recover most of his function...
他的身體機能大部分都能恢復...
...but a stroke like this,  it will limit the hours he can work...
但經歷如此一次中風  會限制他的工作時間
...the information he can process.
以及他可以處理的信息量
Are you okay, Mr. Hoover?
你沒事吧 胡佛先生？
Yes, I'm fine. I just... I was playing  with my dog in the yard on Saturday.
我沒事 我只是...  我週六在院子裡和狗玩了一會兒
Perhaps it's dehydration.
可能只是脫水了
That could do it, but it may be wise  to reduce your hours as well.
或許是原因  但您也減少一些工作時間可能更明智
At your age, it's important to take leave.
在您這個年紀  休息很重要
Miss Gandy, please, give us some privacy.
甘迪 讓我們單獨談談
Let me tell you, if you ever denigrate me  in front of my staff again...
這麼跟你說吧  你要是膽敢再在我的同事面前說我的不是...
...I'll have you railroaded out of your  profession. Understand?
我會讓你前途盡毀  明白了嗎？
I apologize, sir.
我很抱歉
Tell me something.
跟我說說
What do you have for energy?
有什麼東西可以補充能量嗎？
We have diet medications  which tend to give a boost.
我們有節食的藥物  可以有所幫助
So I could lose a few pounds  and have more energy as well?
所以如果我減掉點體重  就會有更多能量？
Wouldn't worry about your weight, sir.  It's solid weight.
不要擔心您的體重  那是結實的重量
Hmm.
嗯
Schedule a daily visit.
安排一下日常的檢查
Yes, sir.
是
They're giving King the Nobel Prize.  Can you believe it?
他們要把諾貝爾和平獎頒給馬丁·路德·金了  你相信嗎？
The degenerates and radicals  are being lifted up internationally.
這些敗類和激進分子  已經在國際上都被捧起來了
It's like it's 1920 all over again.
就像1920年的情況又回來了
Don't.
別
When he finds out  that we have this audiotape...
當他發現  我們有這卷錄音帶...
...that we know the truth  about his character...
我們知道他真正是怎樣一個人...
...he's going to decline the award,  Clyde, believe me.
他肯定要拒絕領獎  克萊德 相信我
President Johnson...
約翰遜總統...
Wait.
等等
- Clyde.  - Wait.
- 克萊德  - 等等
You're gonna have to learn to enunciate.  I can't seem to understand you.
你得學著簡潔一點說話  我好像都要聽不懂你了
We have no legal tools.
現在的問題是  我們沒有合法的手段
You see, our laws have not kept pace...
你看 我們的法律還沒跟上...
...with the improved tactics  of today's criminals.
今天這些犯罪分子不斷進步的戰術
I'm gonna do this for you.
我來幫你
What's your idea?
你怎麼想？
Well, we have friends in the press, right?
我們有在媒體的朋友 對吧？
We plant stories with them to ensure...
我們捏造故事 讓他們...
...that the activities of suspected radicals  see the light of day.
這些可疑的激進分子的行為  全部暴露出來
They'll trace it.
他們會追蹤消息來源
Well, only if it's true.
除非都是真的
See, it's called counterintelligence,  Clyde.
你看 這就叫反間諜 克萊德
The more untrue the story,  the more dramatic the impact.
故事越是被捏造  影響力就越戲劇化
Now, I'm going to send  the hotel recording...
現在 我要把這個賓館錄音帶...
...along with a personal letter  the day before he gets the Nobel Prize.
和一封私人信件一起  在諾貝爾獎頒獎前一天寄給他
And if he accepts the award,  we'll send the tape straight to the press.
如果他接受了這個獎  我們就直接把錄音帶發到媒體
Are you sure that you want to be involved  with that kind of surveillance?
你確定你想要捲入  這次的監視？
Well, that's why the letter  won't be from me.
這就是為什麼這封信  不會是我寫的
It'll be a fictitious letter  from one of his own.
會是捏造成  他自己手下寫的
Then there can be no room for error.  I'm not sure that we could ensu...
那就不允許任何的翻錯了  我不確定我們能...
I cannot understand what  you're saying, Clyde. Please.
我聽不懂你在說什麼了 克萊德
Come on now. Learn to speak up.
你要學著說話有點底氣
Now, listen, I'm gonna need you  in the office tomorrow. No time to relent.
聽著 我要你明天來辦公室  這次沒得商量
I can't.
我不行
Yes, you can.
你當然行
Now eat.
吃吧
You'd think after all this time  she'd be able to cook my egg correctly.
你會看到這麼長時間以後  她終於能把我的雞蛋做好了
What exactly are in these shots?
這注射的都是什麼？
Oh, it's just vitamins...
只是維他命...
...a little extra pick-me-up.
還有一些提神的
"Look into your heart.
「看看你的內心」
You know you are a complete fraud  and a great liability to all of us Negroes."
「你知道你自己是個大騙子  對我們所有黑人都有責任」
I said "us," Miss Gandy, "us," not "the."
我說的是「我們」  甘迪 「我們」 不是 「我」
You're a Negro now, sir?
您現在是黑人了？
Write every word as I say it,  is that understood?
把我說的每個字都寫下來  明白了嗎？
Now, "White people in this country  have enough frauds of their own...
「這個國家的白人騙子已經夠多了...」
...but they do not  have one at this time...
「但他們這次沒有...」
...that is anywhere near your equal.
「沒有任何人能和你相比」
- I repeat..."  - Sir, what is this exercise?
- 「我要重申...」  - 這是做什麼用的？
Miss Gandy, I am not going to entertain  questions during my dictation, now write.
甘迪 我在口述的時候沒時間回答問題  快寫
"I repeat, you are a colossal fraud  and an evil, vicious one, at that!
「我要重申 你是一個大騙子  充滿罪惡 狠毒的人」
You do not believe in God. You do not  believe in any personal moral principles!"
「你並不信仰上帝  你並不信仰任何道德準則！」
Sir, may I ask who this  will be addressed to...
我能不能問問這封信要寄給誰...
The question is not to whom,  Miss Gandy, not to whom...
問題不是寄給誰  甘迪 不是寄給誰
...but from whom and it is not from  this office, is that understood?
而是誰寄的 並且絕對不是從這裡寄出的  明白了嗎？
"You have turned out to be not a leader...
「你其實不是一個領導人...」
...but a dissolute, abnormal,  moral imbecile.
「而是一個放蕩的 變態的  道德低下的人」
There's only one thing left to do  and you know what that is.
「只有一件事你能做了  你也知道怎麼做」
There's but one way out,  and you better take it...
「只有這條出路  你最好接受...」
...before your filthy, abnormal,  fraudulent self is bared to this nation."
「在你這些骯髒的 變態的 欺詐的行為  暴露在這個國家之前」
Did you get everything?
都記下來了嗎？
- Edgar.  - Type it up.
- 埃德加  - 打出來
Type it up.
打出來
I understand that you work for our  PR department, is that correct?
我瞭解到你在我們人事部門工作  是嗎？
For two years now, sir.
是的現在兩年了
Then you are familiar  with my earlier work...
那你應該熟悉我早期的工作...
...against Edward Clarke  and his Ku Klux Klan, are you not?
對抗愛德華·克拉克  還有他的3K黨 是吧？
Yes, sir.
是的
He was arrested for a violation  of the white slave traffic act...
他因為違反販賣白奴法  的暴力行為而被捕...
...for crossing state lines  to have an affair with a white woman.
因為他穿越州界  跟一個白人女人有婚外情
Ls that correct, sir?
是這樣嗎？
That is correct. It was the strongest law  at my disposal at the time.
是的 那是那時候我處理過的最高的法律了
I'll have you know  that I'm very proud of that work.
你要知道  我非常為那件事自豪
Miss Gandy told me that you stopped  with Bruno Hauptmann's arrest.
甘迪小姐告訴我  您上次停在了布魯諾·哈普特曼的逮捕這裡
- Would you like to start there?  - Yes, yes, I think we shall.
- 您想要從那裡開始嗎？  - 是的 就從那裡
Mr. Hauptmann was brought to trial...
哈普特曼被送去庭審
...on January 2nd, 1935.
時間是1935年1月1日
H.L. Mencken called this  the biggest story since the resurrection.
H. L. 門肯（記者）稱  這是基督復活以來最大的新聞
From the looks of things,  this may be bigger.
從現在的情況看  可能還要更大
Well, you see, no two saws  make the same markings.
你們看  沒有兩把鋸子會形成一樣的斷面
This saw from Bruno Hauptmann's  tool chest makes markings identical...
布魯諾·哈普特曼工具箱中的鋸子  留下的鋸痕...
...to those found on the ladder  used in the crime.
和犯罪現場留下的梯子的痕跡一樣
In the ransom note  and Mr. Hauptmann's writings...
比較贖金字條和哈普特曼的筆跡...
...he wrote the word "anyding"  for "anything", uh, "gut" for "good"...
他把「anything（任何事）」寫成「anyding」  把「good（好）」寫成「gut」
..."boad" for "boat,"  and notice the inverted capital N's.
把「boat（船）」寫成「boad」  並且注意這些寫反了的大寫的「N」
And the Y's that look like J's.
還有這些看上去像「J」的「Y」
Mr. Lindbergh, you said you heard a voice...
林德伯格先生  你說你聽到了聲音...
...in the cemetery that night.
在那天晚上的典禮上
Yes, very clearly.
是的 非常清楚
A voice,  to the best of my belief...
一個說話聲  我非常肯定...
...calling Dr. Condon in a foreign accent.
是用一個外國口音叫康登醫生
"Hey, doctor."
「嘿 醫生」
Since that time...
從那個時候...
...have you heard the same voice?
你有沒有聽過一樣的聲音？
Yes, I have.
我有
Whose voice was it  that you heard in the cemetery that night...
那天晚上的典禮你聽到的聲音是誰的...
...saying, "Hey, doctor"?
說道「嘿 醫生」？
That was Hauptmann's voice.
那是哈普特曼的聲音
But did he act alone?
但他到底是不是單獨行動的？
He never confessed,  but what sociopath ever does?
他從未承認  但這些反社會的人什麼時候承認過？
The evidence was clear.
證據確鑿
He was indicted for murder in the  first degree while perpetrating a burglary.
他被控訴犯有一級謀殺  同時犯下重大盜竊
In New Jersey,  that is punishable by death.
在新澤西  這是死罪
Mr. Hauptmann...
哈普特曼先生
...you've had an opportunity  in this courtroom today...
今天 在這個法庭 你有機會...
...to tell the whole truth.
說出所有真相
Have you told the truth?
你有說過真相嗎？
I told the truth already.
我已經說過了
And the statements...
還有那些...
...to District Attorney Foley.  Did you tell him the truth?
對弗萊律師的陳述  你對他說的都是真的嗎？
To a certain extent.
某種程度來說
To a certain extent you didn't  tell him the truth. Ls that right?
那從某種程度來說 你沒說出真相  是不是？
This board that was found  in your closet, S-204...
這塊板子是從你的衣櫥找到的  寫了「S-204」
...has these numbers written on it.
寫了這些數字
It's a little blurred now, isn't it?
現在有點模糊了是不是？
Looks like it.
看上去是
Between are some words.  It looks like Decatur and Sedgwick.
這之間還有幾個字  看上去像「迪凱特」和「賽德維克」
You see that?
看見沒有？
You know what that means, don't you?  That address on there?
你知道這是什麼意思吧？  那裡的地址？
Not exactly.
不大清楚
It is the address and telephone number  of Dr. Condon...
這是不是康登醫生的住址和電話...
...the man who paid the ransom...
付了贖金的人..
...written in your writing,  found on a board in your closet.
你的字跡  在你的衣櫥裡找到
Mr. Hoover, the doctor's here to see you.
胡佛先生 醫生來看你了
Following Dr. King's historic speech...
在馬丁·路德·金的歷史性演講以後...
...many said that day brought about a new  awakening in the conscience of the nation.
很多人說那一天重新喚醒了  這個國家的良知
Others called it a national disgrace.
而其他人則稱這是國家的恥辱
In the long history of man's cruelty to man,  this was a day of hope.
在人與人互相殘殺的歷史長河裡  這是充滿希望的一天
I have a dream...
我有一個夢想...
...that one day...
就是有一天...
...this nation will rise up...
這個國家會站起來
...and live out the true meaning  of its creeds.
發掘信條的真正含義
A man's legacy is determined by where  the story ends, Agent Owens.
一個人留下的東西由故事的結尾決定  歐文斯探員
Let's think about that tonight  and make a decision tomorrow.
今晚好好想想  明天做決定
Ls this about a man's legacy?
這是關乎個人的遺產？
Or an institution's reputation?
還是整個機構的名譽？
The two are connected, Agent Owens.
這兩者是相關的
One invented the other and vice versa.
前者引出了後者 反之亦然
Good day to you.
日安
Yes, sir.
是
We the jury find the defendant,  Bruno Richard Hauptmann...
我們陪審團 判定被告  布魯諾·理查德·哈普特曼...
...guilty of murder in the first degree.
犯有一級謀殺罪
Your Honor,  I ask for immediate sentencing.
法官大人  我請求立即宣判
According to the law of this state...
根據州法律
...l rule that Mr. Bruno Hauptmann  suffer death...
我判決布魯諾·哈普特曼死刑
...at the time and place  and in the manner provided by law.
此時此地  一切依據法律
It's death for Hauptmann!
哈普特曼被判死刑了！
The trial of the century...
世紀大審判...
...the criminal shamed,  the FBl cemented as the public hero.
犯罪分子伏法  聯邦調查局成為了公眾的英雄
That's our, that's our ending, agent.
這就是我們的結尾 探員
But did he do it alone?
但他是不是單獨犯案的？
Is he the one who actually took the child?  How can you be sure?
當時是不是他本人帶走了孩子？  你怎麼能確定？
Well, the mountain of evidence  we discovered, uncovered...
鐵證如山  我們發現了...
...confirmed, and clarified,  you cannot dispute it.
揭開了真相 確認了一切  你不能有什麼爭議了
- Clarence Darrow did.  - Of course. Heh.
- 但是克拉倫斯·達洛懷疑過  - 當然
Of course, Agent Owens.  That's what he does.
當然 歐文斯探員  他懷疑過
Mrs. Roosevelt issued  a statement questioning his guilt.
羅斯福夫人發佈了一項聲明  質疑了他的罪行
Well, she has enough to hide on her own  when it comes to un-American activities.
說到非美國人的行為呢  她自己有的是東西要遮掩
Well, if you're comfortable with it  as an ending, I'll do my best with it.
如果您覺得這個作為結尾合適  我會努力做好
Yes. Yes, I am.
是 好的
Sir.
告辭
Watch this with me.
和我一起看這個
He received my letter  and the audio tape last night.
他昨晚收到了我的信和錄音帶
President Johnson affixes his signature...
約翰遜總統..
...using more than 100 pens.
用了100多支筆簽名
One of the coveted souvenirs  goes to the Nobel prize-winner...
又一份令人垂涎的紀念品  會頒發給諾貝爾獎得主...
...Martin Luther King,  a dedicated leader...
...馬丁·路德·金  一位盡心盡責的領導人...
Go on, say it, Clyde.
說吧 克萊德
It just seems so risky, Edgar,  over a couple negative articles.
埃德加 這很有風險  在這些負面報道之後
He's deliberately surrounded himself  with communists...
他故意讓周圍圍繞著一群共產主義分子...
...and, with the power he's gathering,  he's now our greatest domestic threat.
有了這些他正在集合的力量  他現在正是我們國家內部最大的威脅
On behalf of the Nobel Committee...
代表諾貝爾獎委員會...
...we hand over to you the insignia...  - He's going to decline the award, Clyde.
- 我們把這個...  - 他會拒絕這個獎的 克萊德
He knows what we have can ruin him.
他知道我們手裡的東西可以毀了他
- -Of the Nobel Peace Prize,  the diploma and the gold medal.
這項諾貝爾獎  證書 和金牌
There's no question about it.
毫無疑問
He's done.
他完了
I accept the Nobel Prize for Peace...
我接受這項諾貝爾和平獎...
...at a moment when 22 million Negroes  of the United States...
此刻美國有2200萬黑人
...are enga...
正在...
- Sorry to interrupt, sir.  - Your next appointment is here.
抱歉打擾了  您的下一個約見的人到了
The doctor first, Miss Gandy.
甘迪 讓醫生先進來
Yes, of course.
是的 當然
Send him in in a few minutes. Thank you.
讓他幾分鐘後進來 謝謝
Stay strong, Edgar.
要堅強 埃德加
You stay strong, Edgar.
你要堅強 埃德加
Stay strong. Unh!
要堅強
The parade as it makes its way...
遊行隊伍正在向前...
...to the Capitol Building  for the inauguration.
去往國會大廈的就職儀式
You can see the Roosevelt High  Marching Band leading the way.
可以看到羅斯福軍樂隊  正在帶路
The motorcade is making progress  down Pennsylvania Avenue...
汽車隊伍正在沿著賓夕法尼亞大道前進
...carrying our 37th president.
載著我們的第37任總統
Richard Milhous Nixon  waves to the crowd.
理查德·米爾豪斯·尼克松向群眾招手
Yep, there's the president  and his wife Pat...
是的 總統和他的夫人...
...happily waving.
高興地揮手
When morals decline...
當道德敗壞...
...and good men do nothing...
好人不做任何事...
...evil flourishes.
罪惡就會興盛
Every citizen has a duty to learn of this  that threatens his home...
每個公民都有義務瞭解這些
...his children.
威脅到他們的家園和孩子
A society uninterested and unwilling  to learn from the past...
一個沒興趣也不願意  從過去吸取教訓的社會
...is doomed.
注定會隕滅
We must never forget our history.
我們永遠不能忘記歷史
We must never lower our guard.
我們永遠不能放鬆警惕
Even today, there are organizations  that have America as their prime target.
甚至今天 仍舊有組織  把美國作為他們的頭號目標
They would destroy the safety  and the happiness of every individual...
他們會毀掉每個人的平安和幸福
...and thrust us into  a condition of lawlessness...
把我們推入無法無天的深淵
...immorality that passes the imagination.
超乎想像的無恥
The president will see you now,  Mr. Hoover.
總統先生可以見您了  胡佛先生
Alrighty.
好的
Edgar, come in.
埃德加 進來
Oh, I am so sorry, Mr. Hoover.
噢 我很抱歉 胡佛先生
You weren't answering your telephone.
你一直不接電話
You had a photo session  with a retiring agent.
你和一位要退休的探員有會議
He's leaving now.
他就要走了
Where's Clyde?
克萊德呢？
It's a bad day for him, sir.
他今天不太舒服
Will you...? Will you schedule  a dinner for us, please...
你能不能幫我們安排一下晚餐？
...in our old corner booth?
就在我們轉角的餐廳 老地方
I'm afraid he's too tired today, sir.
恐怕他今天真的太累了
Perhaps you'd like to dine at his house?
或許你願意去他家裡吃？
I think he'd like that.
我想他喜歡這樣
Yes.
好
Yes, thank you, Miss Gandy.
好的 謝謝你 甘迪
Helen?
海倫？
Yes?
嗯？
Do I kill everything that I love?
我是不是毀了一切我所愛的？
He's not gone yet, Edgar.
他還沒有離開 埃德加
And everything that we've built?
還有我們親手建立的一切？
No.
不
The Bureau is stronger  than just you and me now.
調查局比開始只有我們的時候  要強大多了
Your child is sure  and keeps this country safe.
您的部下很可靠  他們保證著國家的安全
Helen, if any...
海倫 假如...
if anything ever happens to me, I need you  to do something for me, do you understand?
假如我出了什麼事  我需要你做點事 你明白嗎？
Of course.
當然
Nixon, he's gonna come for it all.
尼克松 他會追查一切
He'll crucify me and my Bureau.
他會毀了我和我的調查局
I'm afraid of what will happen  if I'm not here to protect it, Miss Gandy.
我擔心假如我不在  會發生些什麼事
Your private files, sir?
您的機密文件？
Then no one will ever find them.
沒有人會找到這些文件
Thank you, Helen.
謝謝你 海倫
No matter what kind of pressure  they put on?
不管他們給你施加多少壓力？
No matter how much?
不管多少？
Yes, Edgar.
是的 埃德加
No matter how much pressure.
不管施加多少壓力
I promise you.
我向你保證
Thank you, Helen.
謝謝你 海倫
Well, did Nixon ask for your resignation?
尼克松有沒有讓你辭職？
No, he wanted to know  what we had in the files on him.
不 他想要知道  我們掌握了他的什麼文件
What did you say?
你說了什麼？
I said, "What files, sir?"
我說「什麼文件？」
But he knows.
但是他知道
He wants us to expand our wiretaps  to include news reporters now, Clyde.
他想讓我們擴大我們的竊聽範圍  包括新聞報道員 克萊德
We can't do that, especially not now.
我們不能那樣做  尤其是現在
That's the problem, Clyde.
問題就在這 克萊德
If I don't agree to do his black bag jobs,  he'll create his own private force.
如果我不答應他做這些暗地裡的事  他會成立自己的私人集權
Oh, that's illegal.
噢 那是違法的
Yes, well, he didn't say it outright,  but I saw it in his eyes.
是啊 他雖然沒有直說  但我可以從他眼神裡看出來
He won't be controlled, Clyde.
他不會受任何人控制 克萊德
He's a menace who'll do anything  to hold on to power.
他是個威脅  他會為了權力做任何事
Right. I see.
是啊 我知道了
Yes. See, I never played his game,  that's the problem.
是啊 你看 我從不跟他玩這些  這就是問題所在
And if to some what I did  seemed like rule-bending...
假如我做的某些事情  看上去有些過界...
...then perhaps they need to figure out  what it is they did...
或許他們需要找出  他們都做了些什麼...
...that made them feel blackmailed  or intimidated.
來讓他們感到被勒索或是恐嚇
I wasn't thinking that.
我想的不是這個
Then what? What were you thinking?
那是什麼？你在想什麼？
I was thinking it might be time  for us to retire.
我在想 或許是時候我們該退休了
Shut up, Clyde.
閉嘴 克萊德
You built a great thing, Edgar.
你有很偉大的成就 埃德加
And if you stop now,  you'll be celebrated.
如果你現在就收手  你會得到嘉獎
That's what you've  always wanted, isn't it?
這是你一直想要的 不是嗎？
Our country's lasting adoration?
整個國家長久的崇拜？
Well, there's a chance you could have it.
現在就是你獲得這些的機會
Yes. Yes, and why wouldn't I? Hmm?
是啊 是啊 我憑什麼不呢？
Why wouldn't I, Clyde?
我憑什麼不呢 克萊德？
I saved this country  from a Bolshevik invasion...
我保衛國家不受布爾什維克侵略
...rid this country of radicals,  captured Machine Gun Kelly...
掃除了激進分子  逮捕了「機關鎗凱利」
...killed Dillinger, captured Karpis,  convicted Bruno Hauptmann.
殺了迪林傑 抓住了卡佩斯  還把布魯諾·哈普特曼定罪了
And now, with my last breath  when I try to help save this country again...
現在 我還有最後一口氣  想要保衛這個國家...
...I'm rewarded with a forced retirement?
結果卻被強制要求退休？
I will not go down,  and the fact that you suggest that...
我不會被打倒的  你這建議其實讓我...
...makes me question your very loyalty.
懷疑你的忠心
My loyalty, Edgar?
我的忠心 埃德加？
Yes, your loyalty, Clyde.
是啊 你的忠心 克萊德
I read your manuscript, Edgar.
我讀過你的手稿了 埃德加
You didn't arrest Karpis.
你並沒有逮捕卡佩斯
And you know as well as I do  there was no white horse in the street...
你和我一樣清楚  那條街上沒有白馬
...no gun in the back seat.
後座也沒有槍
And you didn't kill Dillinger.  Agent Purvis did.
也不是你殺了迪林傑的  是博維斯探員
But you kept all the glory for yourself.
但你把所有的榮譽據為己有
And Machine Gun Kelly never said,  "Don't shoot, G-Men."
「機關鎗凱利」也從未說過  「不要開槍 官老爺們」
You made that up  to sell comic books, Edgar.
你編造了這些  來賣出漫畫書 埃德加
And when we went to the scene  of the greatest crime of the century...
至於本世紀最大的犯罪案件
...Mr. Lindbergh didn't come out  and shake your hand...
林德伯格先生根本沒有出來  和你握手
...and express his faith in the FBl.
也沒有表達他對調查局的信任
He called you a fussy little man,  and he refused to even meet you.
他說你是挑剔的傢伙  拒絕再次和你見面
And you didn't arrest Hauptmann.
也不是你逮捕了哈普特曼
Agent Sisk did.
是西斯科探員
You weren't even at the scene, Edgar.  Only the photo op.
你甚至都不在現場 埃德加  只有那張照片
Edgar, most of what you wrote  is exaggeration...
埃德加 你寫的大多數都是誇大其詞
...some of it blatant lies, and I don't  even know if you realize it anymore.
很多是明顯的謊言  我甚至都不知道你是否意識到這一點
Edgar...
埃德加
...you can lie to everyone else,  the whole world...
你可以對所有人說話  對全世界
...for your own sake,  for the sake of the Bureau...
看在你自己份上  看在調查局的份上
...but you cannot lie to me.
但你騙不了我
I should've never given you  your job, Clyde.
我就不應該給你這份工作 克萊德
You know that?
你知道嗎？
You weren't even qualified.
你根本不符合要求
You remember the day  you came in for your interview?
你記得那天你進來面試嗎？
I do.
我記得
You walked into my office  and you fixed my window...
你來到我的辦公室  幫我整理好了窗戶
...you picked up my handkerchief.
你拿了我的手帕
You handed it to me.
你把它遞給我的
You remember why I was sweating,  Clyde?
你記不記得為什麼我會出汗？
It's because you were exercising.
因為你剛剛鍛煉過
No, I was...
不 我...
I was sweating because I...
我出汗是因為我...
I knew at that very moment...
那一刻我知道...
I knew at that very moment that I...
那一刻我清楚地知道...
I needed you.
我需要你
And I've never needed anyone else  in my entire life.
我這輩子從未需要過其他任何人
Not like that.
從未像你這樣
So I began to perspire.
所以我開始出汗
I know.
我知道
Edgar, are you all right?
埃德加 你沒事吧？
Yes, yes, it's...
是 這是...
It's just indigestion, Clyde.
只是消化不良 克萊德
Let's go to dinner tomorrow night,  shall we? Our old corner booth.
我們明天出去吃晚飯吧？  我們的老地方
Perhaps if I feel better.
或許吧如果我感覺好些了
Yes.
好
And you must...
你必須...
You must...  We have a great many things to discuss.
你必須...  我們還有很重要的事情要商量
And now I can't trust anyone else  at the Bureau right now.
現在在調查局  我沒有任何人可以信任
Can only depend on you.
只能靠你了
Thank you, Edgar.
謝謝你 埃德加
Good night, Clyde.
晚安 克萊德
Good night, Edgar.
晚安 埃德加
Welcome home, Mr. Hoover.
歡迎回家 胡佛先生
Oh, thank you, Annie.
謝謝 安妮
Bozo, Bozo, G-Boy, come here.
波佐 波佐 好孩子 過來
The very essence of our democracy...
民主的本質...
...is rooted in a belief  in the worth of the individual.
扎根於對於獨立的信仰
That life has meaning that transcends  any man-made system...
生命的意義已經超越任何人造系統
...that love is the greatest force  on earth...
愛是世上最偉大的力量
...far more enduring than hatred...
比仇恨要持久得多
...or the unnatural divisions of mankind.
或是人類那些非自然的種群
Yes?
喂？
This is Annie from Mr. Hoover's residence.
我是胡佛先生家的安妮
Mr. Hoover has passed.
胡佛先生去世了
- Yeah?  - Sir.
Jesus Christ.
上帝啊
That old cocksucker.
那個老不死的
I'll get a speech prepared.  We should go on television.
我要準備一個演講  要上電視
Not yet.
還不行
First seal off his office, change his locks,  do whatever you have to do.
先封鎖他的辦公室 換掉鎖  做你應該做的
I want those fucking files.
我得把那些該死的文件找出來
Yes, sir.
是
Oh, good.
真好
Come in.
進來吧
He's upstairs.
他在樓上
Ladies and gentlemen, it is with  a profound sense of personal loss...
女士們先生們  這於我個人也是極大的損失...
...that I learned of the death  of J. Edgar Hoover.
我已得知  J·埃德加·胡佛先生去世了
This truly remarkable man  has served his country for 48 years...
這位了不起的公僕  為國家工作了48年
...under eight presidents,  as director of the FBl...
作為聯邦調查局的局長  歷經8任總統
...with unparalleled devotion  and ability and dedication.
用他無與倫比的奉獻精神  能力 以及巨大貢獻
For 25 years, from the time I came to  Washington as a freshman congressman...
25年以來 從我第一次以新人國會議員  的身份來到華盛頓
...he has been one of my closest  personal friends and advisors.
他就是我最親密的朋友和顧問之一
And every American, in my opinion,  owes J. Edgar Hoover a great debt...
我認為 每個美國人  都欠了胡佛先生很多
...for building the FBl into the finest  law enforcement organization...
他把聯邦調查局  建立成了最好的法律執行機構
...in the entire world.
在全世界的範圍來說
I've ordered that all the flags of the  government buildings be flown at half mast...
我已下令所有的政府機構  都要下半旗致哀
...but I will say that, in doing so,  that Edgar Hoover...
但我要說 這樣做  為了埃德加·胡佛
...because of his indomitable courage  against sometimes very vicious attack...
因為有了他頑強的勇氣  和極其險惡的攻擊作鬥爭
...has made certain that the flag of the FBl  will always fly high.
他已經保證  聯邦調查局的旗幟會一直高高飄揚
The FBl is the eternal monument  honoring this great American.
聯邦調查局是美國永恆的豐碑
Funny how even the dearest face...
「即使這最親密的臉龐..」
...will fade away in time...
「會隨著時間的流逝而消失...」
...but most clearly I remember your eyes  with a sort of teasing smile in them...
「我清楚地記得  你的眼睛裡有挑逗的笑容」
...and the feeling of that soft spot...
「還有那最溫柔的地方...」
...just northeast  of the corner of your mouth.
「是東北方位之於你溫柔的嘴角」
胡佛的「私人機密檔案」從未被人知曉  只有一些沒有歸檔的資料透露出線索
克萊德·托爾森繼承了胡佛的房產 搬進了他家  接受了覆於他棺木的美國國旗
克萊德·托爾森的葬在離胡佛  在國會墓地的墓碑幾碼遠的地方
=完=  翻譯：米粒@豆瓣